<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>life on Steam - a minimal theme for Hugo</title>
    <link>https://example.org/tags/life/</link>
    <description>Recent content in life on Steam - a minimal theme for Hugo</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 20 May 2018 20:11:59 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://example.org/tags/life/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Tracking Metrics to Surface and Solve Problems: Metric Tracking Practices I&#39;ve Learned So Far</title>
      <link>https://example.org/2018/05/21/tracking-metrics-to-surface-and-solve-problems-metric-tracking-practices-ive-learned-so-far/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 May 2018 20:11:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.org/2018/05/21/tracking-metrics-to-surface-and-solve-problems-metric-tracking-practices-ive-learned-so-far/</guid>
      <description>It is a nice pleasant evening, you are sipping coffee and reviewing your code one final time, just so that you can gather enough confidence to hit the deploy button.
But a fact of life as a software engineer is that things can go wrong. Small changes may result in unexpected outcomes, including outages, errors or negatively impacting customers.
And when problems occur, either we can do random checks and validations that may or may not solve the problem or we can have a disciplined problem-solving approach that relies on data rather than intuitions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Alchemist : Reading Experience</title>
      <link>https://example.org/2017/05/22/the-alchemist-reading-experience/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 May 2017 18:28:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.org/2017/05/22/the-alchemist-reading-experience/</guid>
      <description>Reading **The Alchemist **was like getting up at dawn and seeing the sun rise, while the whole world slept.
The Alchemist doesn&amp;rsquo;t teach you anything, but you can learn a million things from it.
&amp;ldquo;Lead will play its role until the world has no further need for the lead, and then the lead will have to turn itself into gold.&amp;rdquo;
My 6th book of the year was **The Alchemist **by Paulo Coelho.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>