<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>catch on Steam - a minimal theme for Hugo</title>
    <link>https://example.org/tags/catch/</link>
    <description>Recent content in catch on Steam - a minimal theme for Hugo</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 20 May 2018 20:11:59 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://example.org/tags/catch/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Tracking Metrics to Surface and Solve Problems: Metric Tracking Practices I&#39;ve Learned So Far</title>
      <link>https://example.org/2018/05/21/tracking-metrics-to-surface-and-solve-problems-metric-tracking-practices-ive-learned-so-far/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 May 2018 20:11:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.org/2018/05/21/tracking-metrics-to-surface-and-solve-problems-metric-tracking-practices-ive-learned-so-far/</guid>
      <description>It is a nice pleasant evening, you are sipping coffee and reviewing your code one final time, just so that you can gather enough confidence to hit the deploy button.
But a fact of life as a software engineer is that things can go wrong. Small changes may result in unexpected outcomes, including outages, errors or negatively impacting customers.
And when problems occur, either we can do random checks and validations that may or may not solve the problem or we can have a disciplined problem-solving approach that relies on data rather than intuitions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contagious : Why Things Catch On : Reading Experience</title>
      <link>https://example.org/2016/02/07/contagious-why-things-catch-on-reading-experience/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Feb 2016 18:29:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.org/2016/02/07/contagious-why-things-catch-on-reading-experience/</guid>
      <description>We all have heard of the hilarious _Panda Cheese _commercial in which a panda screws everyone who says no to panda products. People loved the ad so much that the brand enjoyed world wide recognition. On the other hand commercials by GoldenPalace.com was a complete miss, it just failed to persist their brand name in customer&amp;rsquo;s mind by _Fool in the pool _marketing stunt.
So, what makes things popular? Why do people talk about certain products and ideas more than others?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>