<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>case on Erlich Bachman</title>
    <link>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/tags/case/</link>
    <description>Recent content in case on Erlich Bachman</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 05 Aug 2018 18:41:18 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/tags/case/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Acceptance Tests: The Best Medium of Communication Between Stakeholders (if done right)</title>
      <link>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2018/08/06/acceptance-tests-the-best-medium-of-communication-between-stakeholders-if-done-right/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Aug 2018 18:41:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2018/08/06/acceptance-tests-the-best-medium-of-communication-between-stakeholders-if-done-right/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s a nice pleasant morning, and you have just entered the office. You greet your friends and grab a cup of coffee. You check your email and there is a new story assigned to you.
&amp;ldquo;As a customer, I get my usage logs backed up&amp;rdquo;
This is where is fun begins.
Communicating Requirements A product engineer&amp;rsquo;s job is to have effective and clear communication as much as it is to write code.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Devops and The Principle Of Flow</title>
      <link>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2018/04/29/devops-and-the-principle-of-lean/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Apr 2018 17:01:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2018/04/29/devops-and-the-principle-of-lean/</guid>
      <description>In the technology value stream, work typically flows from Development to Operations, steps consisting of functional areas between our business and our customers.
As stated in the lean principles developed by Toyota, we should optimize to get a single-piece fast and smooth flow for our releases.
We increase flow by:
 1. Making work visible, 2. Reducing batch sizes and intervals of work 3. Building in the quality, preventing defects from being passed to downstream work centers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What to do? An android app made to guide people what to do in various scenarios.</title>
      <link>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2014/06/27/what-to-do-an-android-app-made-to-guide-people-what-to-do-in-various-scenarios/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jun 2014 08:02:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2014/06/27/what-to-do-an-android-app-made-to-guide-people-what-to-do-in-various-scenarios/</guid>
      <description>Click Here to download  _NOTE : _This app has been signed with default debug key
We all face various scenarios in our life . Some are life threatening while some are just awkward moments . In each case it is kinda vital to do the write things at the write time . This app has been made to help you do the same with the help researched content and quick links provided within the app.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>