<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>review on Priyank Verma</title>
    <link>https://priyankvex.github.io/PriyankVermaBlogGenerated/tags/review/</link>
    <description>Recent content in review on Priyank Verma</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 06 Apr 2017 20:39:38 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://priyankvex.github.io/PriyankVermaBlogGenerated/tags/review/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Mastery By Robert Greene : Reading Experience</title>
      <link>https://priyankvex.github.io/PriyankVermaBlogGenerated/2017/04/07/mastery-by-robert-greene-reading-experience/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Apr 2017 20:39:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://priyankvex.github.io/PriyankVermaBlogGenerated/2017/04/07/mastery-by-robert-greene-reading-experience/</guid>
      <description>“The problem with all students, he said, is that they inevitably stop somewhere. They hear an idea and they hold on to it until it becomes dead; they want to flatter themselves that they know the truth. But true Zen never stops, never congeals into such truths. That is why everyone must constantly be pushed to the abyss, starting over and feeling their utter worthlessness as a student. Without suffering and doubts, the mind will come to rest on clichés and stay there, until the spirit dies as well.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Marketing Your Retail Store in the Internet Age by Bob Negen  : Reading Experience</title>
      <link>https://priyankvex.github.io/PriyankVermaBlogGenerated/2016/06/21/marketing-your-retail-store-in-the-internet-age-by-bob-negen-reading-experience/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2016 15:24:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://priyankvex.github.io/PriyankVermaBlogGenerated/2016/06/21/marketing-your-retail-store-in-the-internet-age-by-bob-negen-reading-experience/</guid>
      <description>This was the book that I knew prior to reading it that it won&amp;rsquo;t be too interesting and might even feel too slow. I searched it on the internet and picked it to read to get a perspective of a retail seller. As me and my team are trying to start a company that will work very closely with retail stores and their owners I thought this book will provide some value.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Business in Boxers : 1 Month Into Running a StartUp</title>
      <link>https://priyankvex.github.io/PriyankVermaBlogGenerated/2016/03/22/business-in-boxers-1-month-into-running-a-startup/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Mar 2016 20:49:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://priyankvex.github.io/PriyankVermaBlogGenerated/2016/03/22/business-in-boxers-1-month-into-running-a-startup/</guid>
      <description>**Why the Series? **
(Inspired by book : Business In Blue Jeans)
Hi! This is Priyank. This series is about me pen downing my start-up ride. Don&amp;rsquo;t know if it&amp;rsquo;s fast or slow, all I really know is I&amp;rsquo;m gonna enjoy the ride.
Why the name?
Boxers is what you&amp;rsquo;ll find me almost every time in and business is what&amp;rsquo;s always in my mind and thus the name &amp;ldquo;Business In Boxers&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Losing My Virginity By Richard Branson -  Reading Experience</title>
      <link>https://priyankvex.github.io/PriyankVermaBlogGenerated/2016/01/19/losing-my-virginity-by-richard-branson-reading-experience/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jan 2016 17:10:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://priyankvex.github.io/PriyankVermaBlogGenerated/2016/01/19/losing-my-virginity-by-richard-branson-reading-experience/</guid>
      <description>**Oh, screw it, let&#39;s do it.** That&amp;rsquo;s the philosophy of Richard Branson that has allowed him to start ventures in markets that no one dared to enter and even considered ludicrous to try.
Losing my virginity is the most unusual biography you will ever get to read. It looks like you are reading a biography of not a global entrepreneur but an adventurist.
This is the story of how Richard Branson started his entrepreneur journey by starting the Student magazine and strolled his way to opening more than 400 companies under the Virgin brand.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Outliers: The Story of Success : Reading Review</title>
      <link>https://priyankvex.github.io/PriyankVermaBlogGenerated/2015/11/04/outliers-the-story-of-success-reading-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Nov 2015 17:14:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://priyankvex.github.io/PriyankVermaBlogGenerated/2015/11/04/outliers-the-story-of-success-reading-review/</guid>
      <description>My 6th book of the year was a handpicked one &amp;ldquo;Outliers: The Story of Success&amp;rdquo;. This book was actually recommended to me by my cousin as a &amp;ldquo;must read&amp;rdquo;. And actually I was amazed how great this book is. It takes your intellectual thinking to a roller coaster ride.
As the book description says :
In this stunning new book, Malcolm Gladwell takes us on an intellectual journey through the world of &#34;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rafa  : Reading Experience</title>
      <link>https://priyankvex.github.io/PriyankVermaBlogGenerated/2015/09/05/rafa-reading-experience/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Sep 2015 13:44:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://priyankvex.github.io/PriyankVermaBlogGenerated/2015/09/05/rafa-reading-experience/</guid>
      <description>Here it is. 4th book of the year Rafa by Rafael Nadal and John Carlin.
Being arguably the biggest Rafa fan on this planet this book was in my reading bucket list from a long time. Finally got the opportunity to read this.
This is great in both sense, it gives you a more closer look into the life of your idol and at the same time shows you what does it take to be a champion?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MIT 11.133x : Implementation and Evaluation of Educational Technology – Week 2 Sum Up</title>
      <link>https://priyankvex.github.io/PriyankVermaBlogGenerated/2015/08/04/mit-11-133x-implementation-and-evaluation-of-educational-technology-week-2-sum-up/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Aug 2015 17:21:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://priyankvex.github.io/PriyankVermaBlogGenerated/2015/08/04/mit-11-133x-implementation-and-evaluation-of-educational-technology-week-2-sum-up/</guid>
      <description>Here is it end of week 2 of 11.133x. And we are back with the sum up.
This week was about many aspects that one should deal with while implementing an education technology, like deciding education technology framework, how to analyse a ed tech, technology buying process etc.
This week started with TPACK. What is TPACK and why does it matter?
TPACK is a framework which combines 3 knowledge. These are technological knowledge, content knowledge and pedagogical knowledge.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Passionate Programmer : Reading Experience</title>
      <link>https://priyankvex.github.io/PriyankVermaBlogGenerated/2015/07/22/the-passionate-programmer-reading-experience/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jul 2015 17:36:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://priyankvex.github.io/PriyankVermaBlogGenerated/2015/07/22/the-passionate-programmer-reading-experience/</guid>
      <description>Here we go for the 3rd time. My 3rd book for 2015&amp;rsquo;s 10 book reading challenge is _The Passionate Programmer. _
I picked this book from pragmatic programmer book shelf. All books listed there are awesome and are a must read. Anyways continuing with this book, it was an awesome reading experience. It was one of those books you wish to never end.
The author covers many aspects of what constitutes a not good but a great software developing career.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Agile For Dummies : Reading experience</title>
      <link>https://priyankvex.github.io/PriyankVermaBlogGenerated/2015/06/27/agile-for-dummies-reading-experience/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jun 2015 04:42:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://priyankvex.github.io/PriyankVermaBlogGenerated/2015/06/27/agile-for-dummies-reading-experience/</guid>
      <description>Agile For Dummies
Here we go for the 2nd time. My 2nd book for 2015&amp;rsquo;s 10 book reading challenge is Agile For Dummies.
As I wrote in my previous post I am going to avoid fiction and love stories, but focus more on technical and personal improvement books.
By the time I wrote this post I was in Bangalore for software engineer internship at HealthGraph India. There we were using agile methodology (scrum) for our project.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>6.00.1x: Introduction to Computer Science and Programming Using Python : The Experience</title>
      <link>https://priyankvex.github.io/PriyankVermaBlogGenerated/2014/09/20/6-00-1x-introduction-to-computer-science-and-programming-using-python-the-experience/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Sep 2014 03:09:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://priyankvex.github.io/PriyankVermaBlogGenerated/2014/09/20/6-00-1x-introduction-to-computer-science-and-programming-using-python-the-experience/</guid>
      <description>Hi, guys. I am a very active participant of MOOC. In my previous post I shared my experience with LFS101x : Introduction to linux .And this time I am back with a new course.
It was summer of 2014, I was having my semester break. And 6.00.1x was on my enrollment list on edx. I was really excited to get started with it.
As this course says, it is meant for people with little to no programming experience, I was there having some programming experience but quiet a novice to python.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>