<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Linux on Steam - a minimal theme for Hugo</title>
    <link>https://example.org/tags/linux/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Linux on Steam - a minimal theme for Hugo</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 19 Dec 2016 16:31:50 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://example.org/tags/linux/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>5 notes on MVP architecture pattern for Android</title>
      <link>https://example.org/2016/12/19/5-notes-on-mvp-architecture-pattern-for-android/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Dec 2016 16:31:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.org/2016/12/19/5-notes-on-mvp-architecture-pattern-for-android/</guid>
      <description>Image credits Macoscope  MVP (Model View and Presenter) is an architectural pattern inspired by the popular MVC pattern.
MVP addresses two main points :
 1. Make views as dumb as possible. The dumber the better. 2. Make each layer loosely coupled and easily testable in isolation.  I am using MVP in one of my production project and have used in some dem0 apps. Here are my 5 notes on using MVP for android.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LFS101x : Introduction to Linux on edX</title>
      <link>https://example.org/2014/08/16/lfs101x-introduction-to-linux-on-edx/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Aug 2014 10:13:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.org/2014/08/16/lfs101x-introduction-to-linux-on-edx/</guid>
      <description>It was this summer when I saw this course LFS101x being offered on edX by The Linux Foundation. Both the terms Linux and edX excited me . So I decided to take this course.
My experience with prior online courses I have taken few online courses on edX and coursera . In both the cases I loved the excitement and knowledge they provide. They were also fun learning and thus worked well for me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Starting c/c&#43;&#43; programming in Linux.</title>
      <link>https://example.org/2014/03/11/starting-cc-programming-in-linux/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2014 19:04:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.org/2014/03/11/starting-cc-programming-in-linux/</guid>
      <description>So, guys this post is just a kick off to my blog.
This post is about coding in c or c++ in Linux . So, if you are a beginner looking to get your hand on coding in c or c++ in Linux, this will be of great help.
STEPS:
1.You can use gedit or i recommend you download Sublime Text for Linux.
 Select your language as c/c++ and code and save the file.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>