<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>reading on Erlich Bachman</title>
    <link>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/tags/reading/</link>
    <description>Recent content in reading on Erlich Bachman</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 06 Apr 2017 20:39:38 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/tags/reading/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Mastery By Robert Greene : Reading Experience</title>
      <link>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2017/04/07/mastery-by-robert-greene-reading-experience/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Apr 2017 20:39:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2017/04/07/mastery-by-robert-greene-reading-experience/</guid>
      <description>“The problem with all students, he said, is that they inevitably stop somewhere. They hear an idea and they hold on to it until it becomes dead; they want to flatter themselves that they know the truth. But true Zen never stops, never congeals into such truths. That is why everyone must constantly be pushed to the abyss, starting over and feeling their utter worthlessness as a student. Without suffering and doubts, the mind will come to rest on clichés and stay there, until the spirit dies as well.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zen and the Art of Motorcycle Maintenance : Reading Experience</title>
      <link>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2016/12/25/zen-and-the-art-of-motorcycle-maintenance-reading-experience/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Dec 2016 11:13:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2016/12/25/zen-and-the-art-of-motorcycle-maintenance-reading-experience/</guid>
      <description>The Japanese motorcycle maintenance guide says “ Assembly of Japanese bicycle requires great piece of mind”. There is a thing about everything you build, including bikes. If you build it with non-serene mind, then you build your problems into it.
The book takes you on a cross country bike journey that will teach you mind opening lessons that leave lasting impressions on your mind. Your mind will simple refuse to contract itself to older stage.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Win Friends and Influence People : Reading Experience and Summary</title>
      <link>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2016/07/19/how-to-win-friends-and-influence-people-reading-experience-and-summary/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jul 2016 19:20:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2016/07/19/how-to-win-friends-and-influence-people-reading-experience-and-summary/</guid>
      <description>_How to win friends and influence people _is an all time classic book. I got to know about this book from the _Goodreads _recommendations and instantly decided to read this one. It starts stating that leadership is 15% technical skills and 85% skill to manage human relations. This sentence alone suffices the need of this book.
What you can get out of the book?
 * Gives you new ways to carry on meaningful conversations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Marketing Your Retail Store in the Internet Age by Bob Negen  : Reading Experience</title>
      <link>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2016/06/21/marketing-your-retail-store-in-the-internet-age-by-bob-negen-reading-experience/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2016 15:24:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2016/06/21/marketing-your-retail-store-in-the-internet-age-by-bob-negen-reading-experience/</guid>
      <description>This was the book that I knew prior to reading it that it won&amp;rsquo;t be too interesting and might even feel too slow. I searched it on the internet and picked it to read to get a perspective of a retail seller. As me and my team are trying to start a company that will work very closely with retail stores and their owners I thought this book will provide some value.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Lean Startup : Reading Experience</title>
      <link>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2016/03/28/the-lean-startup-reading-experience/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Mar 2016 21:06:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2016/03/28/the-lean-startup-reading-experience/</guid>
      <description>My 3rd book of the year was The Lean Startup by Eric Ries. I first got to know about the existence of this book during a keynote video of Gary Vaynerchuk where it was up for display. Finally got the time to read it.
The book focuses on how the lean manufacturing using in Toyota can be used in startups as well. And it makes sense! The case studies to new terms defined all help you shape your mind to run your startup in a lean manner.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Business in Boxers : 1 Month Into Running a StartUp</title>
      <link>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2016/03/22/business-in-boxers-1-month-into-running-a-startup/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Mar 2016 20:49:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2016/03/22/business-in-boxers-1-month-into-running-a-startup/</guid>
      <description>**Why the Series? **
(Inspired by book : Business In Blue Jeans)
Hi! This is Priyank. This series is about me pen downing my start-up ride. Don&amp;rsquo;t know if it&amp;rsquo;s fast or slow, all I really know is I&amp;rsquo;m gonna enjoy the ride.
Why the name?
Boxers is what you&amp;rsquo;ll find me almost every time in and business is what&amp;rsquo;s always in my mind and thus the name &amp;ldquo;Business In Boxers&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contagious : Why Things Catch On : Reading Experience</title>
      <link>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2016/02/07/contagious-why-things-catch-on-reading-experience/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Feb 2016 18:29:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2016/02/07/contagious-why-things-catch-on-reading-experience/</guid>
      <description>We all have heard of the hilarious _Panda Cheese _commercial in which a panda screws everyone who says no to panda products. People loved the ad so much that the brand enjoyed world wide recognition. On the other hand commercials by GoldenPalace.com was a complete miss, it just failed to persist their brand name in customer&amp;rsquo;s mind by _Fool in the pool _marketing stunt.
So, what makes things popular? Why do people talk about certain products and ideas more than others?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Outliers: The Story of Success : Reading Review</title>
      <link>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2015/11/04/outliers-the-story-of-success-reading-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Nov 2015 17:14:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2015/11/04/outliers-the-story-of-success-reading-review/</guid>
      <description>My 6th book of the year was a handpicked one &amp;ldquo;Outliers: The Story of Success&amp;rdquo;. This book was actually recommended to me by my cousin as a &amp;ldquo;must read&amp;rdquo;. And actually I was amazed how great this book is. It takes your intellectual thinking to a roller coaster ride.
As the book description says :
In this stunning new book, Malcolm Gladwell takes us on an intellectual journey through the world of &#34;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rafa  : Reading Experience</title>
      <link>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2015/09/05/rafa-reading-experience/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Sep 2015 13:44:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2015/09/05/rafa-reading-experience/</guid>
      <description>Here it is. 4th book of the year Rafa by Rafael Nadal and John Carlin.
Being arguably the biggest Rafa fan on this planet this book was in my reading bucket list from a long time. Finally got the opportunity to read this.
This is great in both sense, it gives you a more closer look into the life of your idol and at the same time shows you what does it take to be a champion?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Agile For Dummies : Reading experience</title>
      <link>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2015/06/27/agile-for-dummies-reading-experience/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jun 2015 04:42:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2015/06/27/agile-for-dummies-reading-experience/</guid>
      <description>Agile For Dummies
Here we go for the 2nd time. My 2nd book for 2015&amp;rsquo;s 10 book reading challenge is Agile For Dummies.
As I wrote in my previous post I am going to avoid fiction and love stories, but focus more on technical and personal improvement books.
By the time I wrote this post I was in Bangalore for software engineer internship at HealthGraph India. There we were using agile methodology (scrum) for our project.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>