<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>marketing on Erlich Bachman</title>
    <link>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/tags/marketing/</link>
    <description>Recent content in marketing on Erlich Bachman</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 05 May 2018 15:56:15 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/tags/marketing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Organization Archetypes And The Concept Of Market-Oriented &#34;Solver Teams&#34;</title>
      <link>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2018/05/05/organization-archetypes-and-the-concept-of-market-oriented-solver-teams/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 May 2018 15:56:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2018/05/05/organization-archetypes-and-the-concept-of-market-oriented-solver-teams/</guid>
      <description>Organizations which designs systems are constrained to produce designs which are copies of the communication structure of the organization.
In other words, how we organize our teams has a powerful effect on the software we produce, as well as our resulting architectural and production outcomes.
Thus, in order to get a fast flow of work from Development to Operations, with high quality, great customer outcomes and fast speed of delivery, we must organize our teams to bring the team structure to our advantage.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Marketing Your Retail Store in the Internet Age by Bob Negen  : Reading Experience</title>
      <link>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2016/06/21/marketing-your-retail-store-in-the-internet-age-by-bob-negen-reading-experience/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2016 15:24:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2016/06/21/marketing-your-retail-store-in-the-internet-age-by-bob-negen-reading-experience/</guid>
      <description>This was the book that I knew prior to reading it that it won&amp;rsquo;t be too interesting and might even feel too slow. I searched it on the internet and picked it to read to get a perspective of a retail seller. As me and my team are trying to start a company that will work very closely with retail stores and their owners I thought this book will provide some value.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Business in Boxers : 1 Month Into Running a StartUp</title>
      <link>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2016/03/22/business-in-boxers-1-month-into-running-a-startup/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Mar 2016 20:49:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2016/03/22/business-in-boxers-1-month-into-running-a-startup/</guid>
      <description>**Why the Series? **
(Inspired by book : Business In Blue Jeans)
Hi! This is Priyank. This series is about me pen downing my start-up ride. Don&amp;rsquo;t know if it&amp;rsquo;s fast or slow, all I really know is I&amp;rsquo;m gonna enjoy the ride.
Why the name?
Boxers is what you&amp;rsquo;ll find me almost every time in and business is what&amp;rsquo;s always in my mind and thus the name &amp;ldquo;Business In Boxers&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UBCx: Marketing1x Introduction to Marketing : Course Experience</title>
      <link>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2016/02/26/ubcx-marketing1x-introduction-to-marketing-course-experience/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Feb 2016 17:22:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2016/02/26/ubcx-marketing1x-introduction-to-marketing-course-experience/</guid>
      <description>Marketing is no longer about the stuff that you make, but about the stories that you tell.
In today&amp;rsquo;s world everyone in some way or another is trying to market themselves to the world. This becomes even more prominent if you are trying to attract customers to earn your living.
_Preping _to become an entrepreneur, I decided to take this course to get the proper understanding of how the mind of a marketer works.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contagious : Why Things Catch On : Reading Experience</title>
      <link>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2016/02/07/contagious-why-things-catch-on-reading-experience/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Feb 2016 18:29:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2016/02/07/contagious-why-things-catch-on-reading-experience/</guid>
      <description>We all have heard of the hilarious _Panda Cheese _commercial in which a panda screws everyone who says no to panda products. People loved the ad so much that the brand enjoyed world wide recognition. On the other hand commercials by GoldenPalace.com was a complete miss, it just failed to persist their brand name in customer&amp;rsquo;s mind by _Fool in the pool _marketing stunt.
So, what makes things popular? Why do people talk about certain products and ideas more than others?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Edx : Digital Branding and Engagement Course Overview And Experience</title>
      <link>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2015/12/19/edx-digital-branding-and-engagement-course-overview-and-experience/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Dec 2015 09:28:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2015/12/19/edx-digital-branding-and-engagement-course-overview-and-experience/</guid>
      <description>People Respond to Effort Lately I have been following Gary Vaynerchuck, an entrepreneur and serial investor. He also owns a social media marketing company Vayner Media. Listening to his podcasts and keynotes is an eye opener on how digital media marketing is reshaping the advertising world.
So I took a course on Edx Digital Branding and Engagement finally know the digital marketing in and out.
The course was 4 weeks long and delivers perfect contextual content.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>