<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>11.133x on Erlich Bachman</title>
    <link>https://priyankvex.github.io/PriyankVermaBlogGenerated/tags/11.133x/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 11.133x on Erlich Bachman</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 23 Aug 2015 18:15:48 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://priyankvex.github.io/PriyankVermaBlogGenerated/tags/11.133x/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>MIT 11.133x : Implementation and Evaluation of Educational Technology – Week 3 Sum Up</title>
      <link>https://priyankvex.github.io/PriyankVermaBlogGenerated/2015/08/23/mit-11-133x-implementation-and-evaluation-of-educational-technology-week-3-sum-up/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Aug 2015 18:15:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://priyankvex.github.io/PriyankVermaBlogGenerated/2015/08/23/mit-11-133x-implementation-and-evaluation-of-educational-technology-week-3-sum-up/</guid>
      <description>What does it take to implement a educational technology? You have the idea that can supposedly change the world of ed tech and learning, but how to implement it?
Throughout the course, in the past 3 weeks I was constantly having my idea of creating an ed tech. With each passing week the course taught me something new which can be used to carve the idea even better.
By the end of 3 weeks I was having a very clear vision of what area of learning I have to target in my ed tech implementation, but again no technical knowledge was there on how to shape up the implementation wire-frame.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MIT 11.133x : Implementation and Evaluation of Educational Technology – Week 2 Sum Up</title>
      <link>https://priyankvex.github.io/PriyankVermaBlogGenerated/2015/08/04/mit-11-133x-implementation-and-evaluation-of-educational-technology-week-2-sum-up/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Aug 2015 17:21:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://priyankvex.github.io/PriyankVermaBlogGenerated/2015/08/04/mit-11-133x-implementation-and-evaluation-of-educational-technology-week-2-sum-up/</guid>
      <description>Here is it end of week 2 of 11.133x. And we are back with the sum up.
This week was about many aspects that one should deal with while implementing an education technology, like deciding education technology framework, how to analyse a ed tech, technology buying process etc.
This week started with TPACK. What is TPACK and why does it matter?
TPACK is a framework which combines 3 knowledge. These are technological knowledge, content knowledge and pedagogical knowledge.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MIT 11.133x : Implementation and Evaluation of Educational Technology – Week 1 Sum Up</title>
      <link>https://priyankvex.github.io/PriyankVermaBlogGenerated/2015/07/26/mit-11-133x-implementation-and-evaluation-of-educational-technology-week-1-sum-up/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jul 2015 18:51:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://priyankvex.github.io/PriyankVermaBlogGenerated/2015/07/26/mit-11-133x-implementation-and-evaluation-of-educational-technology-week-1-sum-up/</guid>
      <description>Here is it. End of week 1 of the course 11.133x.
This week was a little more focused on educational technology. It covered various vital topics like :
 1. Stakeholders in ed tech. 2. Evaluation and assessment. 3. What makes a good ed tech? 4. Future of teaching. 5. Where to start with ed tech? 6. Concept of SAMR.  **Stakeholders in Ed Tech : **
Stakeholders in ed tech are the ones who are going to be affected by the ed tech the most.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MIT 11.133x  : Implementation and Evaluation of Educational Technology - Week 0 Sum Up</title>
      <link>https://priyankvex.github.io/PriyankVermaBlogGenerated/2015/07/19/mit-11-133x-implementation-and-evaluation-of-educational-technology-week-0-sum-up/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jul 2015 05:15:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://priyankvex.github.io/PriyankVermaBlogGenerated/2015/07/19/mit-11-133x-implementation-and-evaluation-of-educational-technology-week-0-sum-up/</guid>
      <description>This week I started with another MOOC by Edx &amp;ldquo;Implementation and Evaluation of Educational Technology&amp;rdquo;. It is a 5 weeks course going from week 0 to week 4.
So here I will blog about my experiences with the course, each week.
WEEK 0
There was not much in the course in week 0. You can guess that by week number.
Week started with introduction to forums and edx platform and how we are supposed to proceed with the course.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>