<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Another on Priyank Verma</title>
    <link>https://priyankvex.github.io/PriyankVermaBlogGenerated/tags/another/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Another on Priyank Verma</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 05 Aug 2018 18:41:18 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://priyankvex.github.io/PriyankVermaBlogGenerated/tags/another/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Acceptance Tests: The Best Medium of Communication Between Stakeholders (if done right)</title>
      <link>https://priyankvex.github.io/PriyankVermaBlogGenerated/2018/08/06/acceptance-tests-the-best-medium-of-communication-between-stakeholders-if-done-right/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Aug 2018 18:41:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://priyankvex.github.io/PriyankVermaBlogGenerated/2018/08/06/acceptance-tests-the-best-medium-of-communication-between-stakeholders-if-done-right/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s a nice pleasant morning, and you have just entered the office. You greet your friends and grab a cup of coffee. You check your email and there is a new story assigned to you.
&amp;ldquo;As a customer, I get my usage logs backed up&amp;rdquo;
This is where is fun begins.
Communicating Requirements A product engineer&amp;rsquo;s job is to have effective and clear communication as much as it is to write code.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Organization Archetypes And The Concept Of Market-Oriented &#34;Solver Teams&#34;</title>
      <link>https://priyankvex.github.io/PriyankVermaBlogGenerated/2018/05/05/organization-archetypes-and-the-concept-of-market-oriented-solver-teams/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 May 2018 15:56:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://priyankvex.github.io/PriyankVermaBlogGenerated/2018/05/05/organization-archetypes-and-the-concept-of-market-oriented-solver-teams/</guid>
      <description>Organizations which designs systems are constrained to produce designs which are copies of the communication structure of the organization.
In other words, how we organize our teams has a powerful effect on the software we produce, as well as our resulting architectural and production outcomes.
Thus, in order to get a fast flow of work from Development to Operations, with high quality, great customer outcomes and fast speed of delivery, we must organize our teams to bring the team structure to our advantage.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Devops and The Principle Of Flow</title>
      <link>https://priyankvex.github.io/PriyankVermaBlogGenerated/2018/04/29/devops-and-the-principle-of-lean/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Apr 2018 17:01:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://priyankvex.github.io/PriyankVermaBlogGenerated/2018/04/29/devops-and-the-principle-of-lean/</guid>
      <description>In the technology value stream, work typically flows from Development to Operations, steps consisting of functional areas between our business and our customers.
As stated in the lean principles developed by Toyota, we should optimize to get a single-piece fast and smooth flow for our releases.
We increase flow by:
 1. Making work visible, 2. Reducing batch sizes and intervals of work 3. Building in the quality, preventing defects from being passed to downstream work centers.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>