<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>principles on Erlich Bachman</title>
    <link>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/tags/principles/</link>
    <description>Recent content in principles on Erlich Bachman</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 29 Apr 2018 17:01:20 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/tags/principles/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Devops and The Principle Of Flow</title>
      <link>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2018/04/29/devops-and-the-principle-of-lean/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Apr 2018 17:01:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2018/04/29/devops-and-the-principle-of-lean/</guid>
      <description>In the technology value stream, work typically flows from Development to Operations, steps consisting of functional areas between our business and our customers.
As stated in the lean principles developed by Toyota, we should optimize to get a single-piece fast and smooth flow for our releases.
We increase flow by:
 1. Making work visible, 2. Reducing batch sizes and intervals of work 3. Building in the quality, preventing defects from being passed to downstream work centers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>8 System Design Principles I learned After Doing It Wrong More than 50 Times!</title>
      <link>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2018/03/11/8-system-design-principles-i-learned-after-doing-it-wrong-more-than-50-times/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Mar 2018 07:16:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2018/03/11/8-system-design-principles-i-learned-after-doing-it-wrong-more-than-50-times/</guid>
      <description>At Squad, we strive to build awesome products to solve customer(internal and external) needs. As a product engineer, paramount part of your job is to design and build products. Dig deep into the root cause of the problems, design solutions and implement them as the end product.
Over the course of my journey so far, here are the 8 system and product design principles that I&amp;rsquo;ve learned from other awesome people at Squad, from feedback and simply doing it not right enough multiple times.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>