<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>startup on Erlich Bachman</title>
    <link>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/tags/startup/</link>
    <description>Recent content in startup on Erlich Bachman</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 26 Jul 2016 09:57:18 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/tags/startup/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>IIMBx: EP101x DO Your Venture : Course Experience on edX</title>
      <link>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2016/07/26/iimbx-ep101x-do-your-venture-course-experience-on-edx/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jul 2016 09:57:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2016/07/26/iimbx-ep101x-do-your-venture-course-experience-on-edx/</guid>
      <description>The best way to win is to show grit and bid on your strengths and intuitions. I have been trying to start my own company now for quite a some time. This course came into my mail box by edX, title looked captivating and thus I decided to take it.
It was a light course. Not much effort needed other that just watching the videos and doing some assignments.
The course was focused on making people get off with their venture from the idea phase to execution phase.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Business In Boxers 3 : The Psychological Roller Coaster</title>
      <link>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2016/06/30/business-in-boxers-3-the-psychological-roller-coaster/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jun 2016 18:58:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2016/06/30/business-in-boxers-3-the-psychological-roller-coaster/</guid>
      <description>One of my favorite things about instrumental music is that the listener is encouraged to use his or her imagination. I have been a huge Owl City and Adam Young fan since forever. Lately he is releasing sets of instrumental music called as Adam Young Scores inspired by incidents that made a lasting impression on the world. Reading about all those incidents has made a lasting impression on my mind for sure, our small failures and success doesn&amp;rsquo;t even matter to the world, we have got to make it large.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Business in Boxers 2 : The Rainbow Shelf</title>
      <link>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2016/05/30/business-in-boxers-2-the-rainbow-shelf/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 May 2016 20:12:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2016/05/30/business-in-boxers-2-the-rainbow-shelf/</guid>
      <description>As a 16-17 year old you try to figure out what you want to do with your life and then you just imagine yourself doing that. I am a kind of person who imagines stuff very vividly. Few years down the time river here I am, trying to work as hard as I can in the scorching summer heat on something that I always wanted to do.
Second month working on the startup I always wanted to do.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Lean Startup : Reading Experience</title>
      <link>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2016/03/28/the-lean-startup-reading-experience/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Mar 2016 21:06:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2016/03/28/the-lean-startup-reading-experience/</guid>
      <description>My 3rd book of the year was The Lean Startup by Eric Ries. I first got to know about the existence of this book during a keynote video of Gary Vaynerchuk where it was up for display. Finally got the time to read it.
The book focuses on how the lean manufacturing using in Toyota can be used in startups as well. And it makes sense! The case studies to new terms defined all help you shape your mind to run your startup in a lean manner.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Business in Boxers : 1 Month Into Running a StartUp</title>
      <link>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2016/03/22/business-in-boxers-1-month-into-running-a-startup/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Mar 2016 20:49:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2016/03/22/business-in-boxers-1-month-into-running-a-startup/</guid>
      <description>**Why the Series? **
(Inspired by book : Business In Blue Jeans)
Hi! This is Priyank. This series is about me pen downing my start-up ride. Don&amp;rsquo;t know if it&amp;rsquo;s fast or slow, all I really know is I&amp;rsquo;m gonna enjoy the ride.
Why the name?
Boxers is what you&amp;rsquo;ll find me almost every time in and business is what&amp;rsquo;s always in my mind and thus the name &amp;ldquo;Business In Boxers&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>