<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Python on Priyank Verma</title>
    <link>https://priyankvex.github.io/PriyankVermaBlogGenerated/tags/python/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Python on Priyank Verma</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 03 Jun 2018 13:14:07 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://priyankvex.github.io/PriyankVermaBlogGenerated/tags/python/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating Outbound Call Warm Transfer Using Twilio In Python and Django</title>
      <link>https://priyankvex.github.io/PriyankVermaBlogGenerated/2018/06/03/creating-outbound-call-warm-transfer-using-twilio-in-python-and-django/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Jun 2018 13:14:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://priyankvex.github.io/PriyankVermaBlogGenerated/2018/06/03/creating-outbound-call-warm-transfer-using-twilio-in-python-and-django/</guid>
      <description>Have you ever been connected to a call where it was transferred to a third person for further assistance? Well, that&amp;rsquo;s call transferring.
Warm transfer of calls, in contrast to cold transfer, doesn&amp;rsquo;t disconnect the call in between and thus gives the customers a more seamless experience.
Recently at work, I was building a system to convert regular calls to a warm transfer if needed. And in this post, I&amp;rsquo;ll be sharing what I learned while building the warm transfer system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Philosophy Behind The Offensive Programming</title>
      <link>https://priyankvex.github.io/PriyankVermaBlogGenerated/2017/07/08/philosophy-behind-the-offensive-programming/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jul 2017 19:30:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://priyankvex.github.io/PriyankVermaBlogGenerated/2017/07/08/philosophy-behind-the-offensive-programming/</guid>
      <description>Recently I was listening to a podcast and there was this really smart guy Piwai talking about something that instantly captivated by attention. That was the coining of the term Offensive Programming.
What is offensive programming?
Well, you can find the literature on Wikipedia and also I am not the best person to explain that. So check that out please. But fundamentally, _offensive programming _refers to a style of programming that is exact opposite of the more famous counter-part the defensive programming.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>6.00.1x: Introduction to Computer Science and Programming Using Python : The Experience</title>
      <link>https://priyankvex.github.io/PriyankVermaBlogGenerated/2014/09/20/6-00-1x-introduction-to-computer-science-and-programming-using-python-the-experience/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Sep 2014 03:09:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://priyankvex.github.io/PriyankVermaBlogGenerated/2014/09/20/6-00-1x-introduction-to-computer-science-and-programming-using-python-the-experience/</guid>
      <description>Hi, guys. I am a very active participant of MOOC. In my previous post I shared my experience with LFS101x : Introduction to linux .And this time I am back with a new course.
It was summer of 2014, I was having my semester break. And 6.00.1x was on my enrollment list on edx. I was really excited to get started with it.
As this course says, it is meant for people with little to no programming experience, I was there having some programming experience but quiet a novice to python.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>