<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>zen on Steam - a minimal theme for Hugo</title>
    <link>https://example.org/tags/zen/</link>
    <description>Recent content in zen on Steam - a minimal theme for Hugo</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 07 Jul 2017 19:30:08 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://example.org/tags/zen/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Philosophy Behind The Offensive Programming</title>
      <link>https://example.org/2017/07/08/philosophy-behind-the-offensive-programming/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jul 2017 19:30:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.org/2017/07/08/philosophy-behind-the-offensive-programming/</guid>
      <description>Recently I was listening to a podcast and there was this really smart guy Piwai talking about something that instantly captivated by attention. That was the coining of the term Offensive Programming.
What is offensive programming?
Well, you can find the literature on Wikipedia and also I am not the best person to explain that. So check that out please. But fundamentally, _offensive programming _refers to a style of programming that is exact opposite of the more famous counter-part the defensive programming.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zen and the Art of Motorcycle Maintenance : Reading Experience</title>
      <link>https://example.org/2016/12/25/zen-and-the-art-of-motorcycle-maintenance-reading-experience/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Dec 2016 11:13:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.org/2016/12/25/zen-and-the-art-of-motorcycle-maintenance-reading-experience/</guid>
      <description>The Japanese motorcycle maintenance guide says “ Assembly of Japanese bicycle requires great piece of mind”. There is a thing about everything you build, including bikes. If you build it with non-serene mind, then you build your problems into it.
The book takes you on a cross country bike journey that will teach you mind opening lessons that leave lasting impressions on your mind. Your mind will simple refuse to contract itself to older stage.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>