<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>entrepreneurship on Erlich Bachman</title>
    <link>https://priyankvex.github.io/PriyankVermaBlogGenerated/tags/entrepreneurship/</link>
    <description>Recent content in entrepreneurship on Erlich Bachman</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 25 Mar 2018 11:32:12 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://priyankvex.github.io/PriyankVermaBlogGenerated/tags/entrepreneurship/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Practical Problem Solving Framework: Inspired By The Toyota Way</title>
      <link>https://priyankvex.github.io/PriyankVermaBlogGenerated/2018/03/25/practical-problem-solving-framework-inspired-by-the-toyota-way/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Mar 2018 11:32:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://priyankvex.github.io/PriyankVermaBlogGenerated/2018/03/25/practical-problem-solving-framework-inspired-by-the-toyota-way/</guid>
      <description>We all will agree to a certain point that having a system/process for anything reduces chances of errors.
As an engineer or someone people look forward to propose solutions to problems it&amp;rsquo;s beneficial to have a framework in place to solve problems effectively.
Recently I was reading _**The Toyota Way, **_and it suggested a framework to _Practical Problem Solving. _It almost felt trivial that this sort of framework would be invaluable to software engineers too (in fact for everyone).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Estimation  Peril:  How To Estimate  Software Projects Effectively(or How Not To Lie)</title>
      <link>https://priyankvex.github.io/PriyankVermaBlogGenerated/2017/10/15/estimation-peril-how-to-estimate-software-projects-effectivelyor-how-not-to-lie/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Oct 2017 17:24:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://priyankvex.github.io/PriyankVermaBlogGenerated/2017/10/15/estimation-peril-how-to-estimate-software-projects-effectivelyor-how-not-to-lie/</guid>
      <description>Consider, you are a rockstar engineer and you are given a task by your favorite person, your project manager, to show some new fields in the dashboard.
As usual, you are asked to estimate it as soon as possible. You think that well, seems like a quickie and you are tempted to estimate it a day. But you, being burnt before, decided to look at the fields that are to be added carefully.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>E-Summit ’17 IIT Bombay — Experience</title>
      <link>https://priyankvex.github.io/PriyankVermaBlogGenerated/2017/02/03/e-summit-17-iit-bombay%e2%80%8a-%e2%80%8aexperience/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Feb 2017 17:16:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://priyankvex.github.io/PriyankVermaBlogGenerated/2017/02/03/e-summit-17-iit-bombay%e2%80%8a-%e2%80%8aexperience/</guid>
      <description>E-Summit is the flagship entrepreneurship event organized by IITB. The two-day annual summit promises to be an amazing meeting ground for industry experts, business leaders, investors and entrepreneurs and of course, students, many of whom are aspiring entrepreneurs.
I attended this event in its 2017 edition and had mixed feelings on how the whole thing turned out holistically. There were some good parts and some not so good parts, but as a whole the event was worth attending.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Blue Ocean Strategy : How To Create Uncontested Market Space and Make the Competition Irrelevant</title>
      <link>https://priyankvex.github.io/PriyankVermaBlogGenerated/2017/01/15/the-blue-ocean-strategy-how-to-create-uncontested-market-space-and-make-the-competition-irrelevant/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Jan 2017 10:49:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://priyankvex.github.io/PriyankVermaBlogGenerated/2017/01/15/the-blue-ocean-strategy-how-to-create-uncontested-market-space-and-make-the-competition-irrelevant/</guid>
      <description>When Henry Ford made cheap, reliable cars people said, ‘Nah, what’s wrong with a horse?’ That was a huge bet he made, and it worked. The whole idea of _The Blue Ocean Strategy _is to create uncontested market spaces that creates new demands and make the competition irrelevant.
The book describes _Red Oceans _as known market places that have bloody competition among businesses trying to win customers. Here there is a fixed existing demand of which every company wants a share.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IIMBx: EP101x DO Your Venture : Course Experience on edX</title>
      <link>https://priyankvex.github.io/PriyankVermaBlogGenerated/2016/07/26/iimbx-ep101x-do-your-venture-course-experience-on-edx/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jul 2016 09:57:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://priyankvex.github.io/PriyankVermaBlogGenerated/2016/07/26/iimbx-ep101x-do-your-venture-course-experience-on-edx/</guid>
      <description>The best way to win is to show grit and bid on your strengths and intuitions. I have been trying to start my own company now for quite a some time. This course came into my mail box by edX, title looked captivating and thus I decided to take it.
It was a light course. Not much effort needed other that just watching the videos and doing some assignments.
The course was focused on making people get off with their venture from the idea phase to execution phase.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>