<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Erlich Bachman</title>
    <link>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Erlich Bachman</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2019 13:29:07 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Dependency Injection: Taming the modules that make up our software.</title>
      <link>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2019/06/25/dependency-injection-taming-the-modules-that-make-up-our-software/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2019 13:29:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2019/06/25/dependency-injection-taming-the-modules-that-make-up-our-software/</guid>
      <description>Introduction All software projects, (even relatively smaller ones) are the result of aggregation of several components and modules. As these software projects grow and evolve, the way we connect these components becomes a win or lose factor.
I believe, that the way we orchestrate these components decides if the software will evolve as fast as the business needs it to, or gets tangled in its own complexity and slows the business down.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Tale on Concatenated Indexes: Master Roshi and Goku&#39;s fireside chat</title>
      <link>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2019/05/19/a-tale-on-concatenated-indexes-master-roshi-and-gokus-fireside-chat/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 May 2019 08:46:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2019/05/19/a-tale-on-concatenated-indexes-master-roshi-and-gokus-fireside-chat/</guid>
      <description>Indexes make our queries run as fast as a cheetah!
Right Practice. Right Results
This post is part of newsletter that I run &amp;ldquo;Scamming the Coding Interview&amp;rdquo;, which is geared towards continuous practice on concepts to ace the engineering interviews.
[
Subscribe
](https://scammingthecodinginterview.com)
Once upon a time there was a master named Roshi whose relational database used to work like a blowing wind.
Reads used to be so fast that it reminded people of thunder strike.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to LSM Trees: May the logs be with you</title>
      <link>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2019/04/28/introduction-to-lsm-trees-may-the-logs-be-with-you/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Apr 2019 10:40:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2019/04/28/introduction-to-lsm-trees-may-the-logs-be-with-you/</guid>
      <description>LSM Trees overview
  This post is a part of a newsletter that I run: “Scamming The Coding Interview“, which is geared towards helping people ACE their coding interviews. We send a coding question on weekdays along with a system design article like this one on weekends. Do subscribe If you find this article valuable.
Introduction What will be the simplest implementation of a database that we can think of?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Architecting for Scale by Lee Atchison: Reading Experience</title>
      <link>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2019/03/07/architecting-for-scale-by-lee-atchison-reading-experience/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2019 15:54:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2019/03/07/architecting-for-scale-by-lee-atchison-reading-experience/</guid>
      <description>I recently read the book Architecting for Scale by Lee Atchison. The book contains a high-level overview of the major concepts that revolve around the topic of building highly-available and scalable apps.
I felt the book to be more suited as a light read for people already familiar with these concepts rather than being an informative book for the new readers.
The book divided into 5 parts mainly:
1. Availability</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How To Objectively Reason About Systems: Correctness Properties Of A System</title>
      <link>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2019/01/06/how-to-objectively-reason-about-systems-correctness-properties-of-a-system/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Jan 2019 15:54:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2019/01/06/how-to-objectively-reason-about-systems-correctness-properties-of-a-system/</guid>
      <description>This post is a part of a newsletter that I run: &amp;ldquo;Scamming The Coding Interview&amp;rdquo;, which is geared towards helping people ACE their coding interviews. We send a coding question on weekdays along with a system design article like this one on weekends. Do subscribe If you find this article valuable.
When a new system is to be designed, the first and the most important step is to generally get the expectations from the system to be crystal clear.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Basics of Database Partitioning and Partition Strategies</title>
      <link>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2018/12/30/basics-of-database-partitioning-and-partition-strategies/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Dec 2018 16:50:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2018/12/30/basics-of-database-partitioning-and-partition-strategies/</guid>
      <description>You are a part of a startup which has recently scaled to reach a huge number of users. This means that the increased number of users are going to generate a huge amount of data that you have to store and manage.
It soon becomes evident that managing a huge dataset is a major hurdle to achieve query efficiency and it might make sense to break the database down into smaller and much more manageable chunks, just like good old low scale days.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why systems fail and what can be done about it?</title>
      <link>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2018/12/22/why-systems-fail-and-what-can-be-done-about-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Dec 2018 15:49:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2018/12/22/why-systems-fail-and-what-can-be-done-about-it/</guid>
      <description>A recent team meeting at Squad touched the topic of &amp;ldquo;system robustness&amp;rdquo;. Clients and business operations want their systems to work, which is a very reasonable expectation. That&amp;rsquo;s what we engineers are paid for after all.
Everybody gave their input over what a robust system means to them. The responses made two points very clear:
1. There is an understanding gap in differentiating, robustness and availability of the system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tackling Lost Updates Problem In Database Using Stricter Transaction  Isolation Level</title>
      <link>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2018/10/20/tackling-lost-updates-problem-in-database-using-better-isolation-level/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Oct 2018 11:40:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2018/10/20/tackling-lost-updates-problem-in-database-using-better-isolation-level/</guid>
      <description>** Introduction**
Databases are made for scale and are a highly concurrent system. Thus it is normal for them to expect multiple concurrent connections.
Also, in most situations, we&amp;rsquo;ll want our database to be the source of truth and always contain consistent data.
There are many concurrency related phenomena that can occur in a database when multiple transactions try to access/modify the same block of data. Ex dirty reads, dirty writes etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Practical Design Patterns Part 1: The Command Pattern</title>
      <link>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2018/09/17/practical-design-patterns-part-1-the-command-pattern/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Sep 2018 07:51:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2018/09/17/practical-design-patterns-part-1-the-command-pattern/</guid>
      <description>** Introduction**
Most software these days support undoing/redoing actions. For example, text editors support undoing what we have written, file managers support undoing file creation/deletion etc. It&amp;rsquo;s a good UX practice to make software forgiving and allow users to undo their actions.
I always wondered how was this implemented? On a critical analysis, it seems as if the object on which the actions are taking place receives them from somewhere else, like a _command.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A plea for lean software: 6 Lessons I learned to help keep software simple</title>
      <link>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2018/09/02/a-plea-for-lean-software-6-lessons-i-learned-to-help-keep-software-simple/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Sep 2018 17:42:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2018/09/02/a-plea-for-lean-software-6-lessons-i-learned-to-help-keep-software-simple/</guid>
      <description>Preface Recently, I was browsing the codebase of my company and saw that it has three versions of dashboards for an analytics page in it. I am pretty sure that customers don&amp;rsquo;t need that. This sparked something in my naive brain and I started exploring the internet for related ideas. That&amp;rsquo;s when I found this age-old paper, A Plea for Lean Software.
This post is largely influenced by ideas presented in the paper that resonated with me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Acceptance Tests: The Best Medium of Communication Between Stakeholders (if done right)</title>
      <link>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2018/08/06/acceptance-tests-the-best-medium-of-communication-between-stakeholders-if-done-right/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Aug 2018 18:41:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2018/08/06/acceptance-tests-the-best-medium-of-communication-between-stakeholders-if-done-right/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s a nice pleasant morning, and you have just entered the office. You greet your friends and grab a cup of coffee. You check your email and there is a new story assigned to you.
&amp;ldquo;As a customer, I get my usage logs backed up&amp;rdquo;
This is where is fun begins.
Communicating Requirements A product engineer&amp;rsquo;s job is to have effective and clear communication as much as it is to write code.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>6 Lessons On Work Ethic I Learned In One Year Of Professional Career</title>
      <link>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2018/07/21/6-lessons-on-work-ethic-i-learned-in-one-year-of-professional-career/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Jul 2018 18:17:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2018/07/21/6-lessons-on-work-ethic-i-learned-in-one-year-of-professional-career/</guid>
      <description>Time flies. Recently I had completed one year as a full-time employee at my current employer **Squad. **A year has passed, and I decided it was time to revisit instances, memories, and experiences and to recollect what I had learned as a professional in this past year.
It was also a wake-up call to reassess and redirect the ship named professional career to make sure it doesn&amp;rsquo;t get stuck in a whirlpool.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating Outbound Call Warm Transfer Using Twilio In Python and Django</title>
      <link>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2018/06/03/creating-outbound-call-warm-transfer-using-twilio-in-python-and-django/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Jun 2018 13:14:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2018/06/03/creating-outbound-call-warm-transfer-using-twilio-in-python-and-django/</guid>
      <description>Have you ever been connected to a call where it was transferred to a third person for further assistance? Well, that&amp;rsquo;s call transferring.
Warm transfer of calls, in contrast to cold transfer, doesn&amp;rsquo;t disconnect the call in between and thus gives the customers a more seamless experience.
Recently at work, I was building a system to convert regular calls to a warm transfer if needed. And in this post, I&amp;rsquo;ll be sharing what I learned while building the warm transfer system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tracking Metrics to Surface and Solve Problems: Metric Tracking Practices I&#39;ve Learned So Far</title>
      <link>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2018/05/21/tracking-metrics-to-surface-and-solve-problems-metric-tracking-practices-ive-learned-so-far/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 May 2018 20:11:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2018/05/21/tracking-metrics-to-surface-and-solve-problems-metric-tracking-practices-ive-learned-so-far/</guid>
      <description>It is a nice pleasant evening, you are sipping coffee and reviewing your code one final time, just so that you can gather enough confidence to hit the deploy button.
But a fact of life as a software engineer is that things can go wrong. Small changes may result in unexpected outcomes, including outages, errors or negatively impacting customers.
And when problems occur, either we can do random checks and validations that may or may not solve the problem or we can have a disciplined problem-solving approach that relies on data rather than intuitions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Organization Archetypes And The Concept Of Market-Oriented &#34;Solver Teams&#34;</title>
      <link>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2018/05/05/organization-archetypes-and-the-concept-of-market-oriented-solver-teams/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 May 2018 15:56:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2018/05/05/organization-archetypes-and-the-concept-of-market-oriented-solver-teams/</guid>
      <description>Organizations which designs systems are constrained to produce designs which are copies of the communication structure of the organization.
In other words, how we organize our teams has a powerful effect on the software we produce, as well as our resulting architectural and production outcomes.
Thus, in order to get a fast flow of work from Development to Operations, with high quality, great customer outcomes and fast speed of delivery, we must organize our teams to bring the team structure to our advantage.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Devops and The Principle Of Flow</title>
      <link>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2018/04/29/devops-and-the-principle-of-lean/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Apr 2018 17:01:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2018/04/29/devops-and-the-principle-of-lean/</guid>
      <description>In the technology value stream, work typically flows from Development to Operations, steps consisting of functional areas between our business and our customers.
As stated in the lean principles developed by Toyota, we should optimize to get a single-piece fast and smooth flow for our releases.
We increase flow by:
 1. Making work visible, 2. Reducing batch sizes and intervals of work 3. Building in the quality, preventing defects from being passed to downstream work centers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>7 Tips On Making Your Engineering Workflow Faster</title>
      <link>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2018/04/23/7-tips-on-making-your-engineering-workflow-faster/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Apr 2018 19:55:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2018/04/23/7-tips-on-making-your-engineering-workflow-faster/</guid>
      <description>One of the most important thing that I like about pair programming with other awesome engineers is you get to see their workflows. How they get things done? How they get find and make their way around tools, terminal, and editors?
After witnessing and getting awestruck by many such experiences I realized that having an effective workflow can increase your day to productivity many folds.
The next step was to take action, and while doing so, I have compiled few tips to make your engineering flow faster too.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fail Fast: Hone Your Ability to Recover and Respond Quickly</title>
      <link>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2018/04/14/fail-fast-hone-your-ability-to-recover-and-respond-quickly/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Apr 2018 18:16:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2018/04/14/fail-fast-hone-your-ability-to-recover-and-respond-quickly/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s close to midnight and you are about to wrap your day off. Suddenly you get a pager-duty to resolve a critical bug that&amp;rsquo;s failing some of the automated reporting emails.
You go on to check the logs in the log management tool. This is not the ideal time to find out that logs are not getting streamed to the log management service properly.
Next, you decide to check the performance metrics of the email API and you realize that you don&amp;rsquo;t know the new monitoring tool well enough to get the right metrics quickly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Strive to learn : 8 Ways to optimize for learning at work as a software engineer</title>
      <link>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2018/04/07/strive-to-learn-8-ways-to-optimize-for-learning-at-work-as-software-engineer/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Apr 2018 15:30:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2018/04/07/strive-to-learn-8-ways-to-optimize-for-learning-at-work-as-software-engineer/</guid>
      <description>A large open space with amazing ergonomic chairs where people discuss and execute upon disrupting ideas. It&amp;rsquo;s right next to company&amp;rsquo;s game room where you unwind after a hard work day. Here is we as engineers, get to work on products that our customers love and we love delivering that delight by continuous delivery (or something else :P).
Yet the most prominent thing that excites and should excite an effective engineer is the opportunity for learning at work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Practical Problem Solving Framework: Inspired By The Toyota Way</title>
      <link>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2018/03/25/practical-problem-solving-framework-inspired-by-the-toyota-way/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Mar 2018 11:32:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2018/03/25/practical-problem-solving-framework-inspired-by-the-toyota-way/</guid>
      <description>We all will agree to a certain point that having a system/process for anything reduces chances of errors.
As an engineer or someone people look forward to propose solutions to problems it&amp;rsquo;s beneficial to have a framework in place to solve problems effectively.
Recently I was reading _**The Toyota Way, **_and it suggested a framework to _Practical Problem Solving. _It almost felt trivial that this sort of framework would be invaluable to software engineers too (in fact for everyone).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>8 System Design Principles I learned After Doing It Wrong More than 50 Times!</title>
      <link>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2018/03/11/8-system-design-principles-i-learned-after-doing-it-wrong-more-than-50-times/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Mar 2018 07:16:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2018/03/11/8-system-design-principles-i-learned-after-doing-it-wrong-more-than-50-times/</guid>
      <description>At Squad, we strive to build awesome products to solve customer(internal and external) needs. As a product engineer, paramount part of your job is to design and build products. Dig deep into the root cause of the problems, design solutions and implement them as the end product.
Over the course of my journey so far, here are the 8 system and product design principles that I&amp;rsquo;ve learned from other awesome people at Squad, from feedback and simply doing it not right enough multiple times.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to Ingressing With Kubernetes</title>
      <link>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2018/02/04/introduction-to-ingressing-with-kubernetes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Feb 2018 14:51:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2018/02/04/introduction-to-ingressing-with-kubernetes/</guid>
      <description>Single responsibility is a magical notion. Whatever it touches, it makes it more manageable and efficient.
With _Kubernetes, _we have the power to spawn many services. As many of them as we would like. But how inbounds requests are routed among these services?
_Ingressing _is a powerful way to decouple routing rules with core application logic.
According to kubernetes,
Ingress is a collection of rules that allow inbound connections to reach to reach cluster services.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2018, New Year: Let&#39;s Set The Rhythm For What Lies Ahead</title>
      <link>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2018/01/01/2018-new-year-lets-set-the-rhythm-for-what-lies-ahead/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2017 19:35:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2018/01/01/2018-new-year-lets-set-the-rhythm-for-what-lies-ahead/</guid>
      <description>Here are the 9 things I would love to incorporate into my life as I set myself to see the sun of 2018.
1. Stop chasing the long dream, start conquering the micro-goals: Start cultivating a passionate dedication to the pursuit of short-term goals, being micro ambitious. Putting my head down and work with pride, whatever is the job in the hand. If we see too far in front of us, we won&amp;rsquo;t see shiny thing right in front of us.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Basics Of Kubernetes Volume Management :  Mounting a simple hostPath directory</title>
      <link>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2017/12/24/basics-of-kubernetes-volume-management-mounting-a-simple-hostpath-directory/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Dec 2017 20:02:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2017/12/24/basics-of-kubernetes-volume-management-mounting-a-simple-hostpath-directory/</guid>
      <description>Kubernetes is a system for automating deployment, scaling, and management for containerized applications.
As we know, containers, which create the Pods, are ephemeral in nature. All data stored inside a container is deleted if the container crashes. However, kubelet will restart it with a clean state, which means that it will not have any of the old data.
To overcome this problem, Kubernetes uses Volumes. A Volume is essentially a directory backed by a storage medium.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deploying a nginx application using Kubernetes for Self-Healing and Scaling</title>
      <link>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2017/11/19/deploying-a-nginx-application-using-kubernetes-for-self-healing-and-scaling/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Nov 2017 15:50:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2017/11/19/deploying-a-nginx-application-using-kubernetes-for-self-healing-and-scaling/</guid>
      <description>Kubernetes is an open source system for automating deployment, scaling and management of containerized applications. A more technical term for it is, container orchestrator which is used to manage large fleets of containers.
Minikube is an all-in-one single node installation for trying out kubernetes on local machines. And the following post covers deploying a nginx application container using kubernetes in minikube.
If you don&amp;rsquo;t have, then this link has it all to install minikube and kubectl (command line tool to access minikube) : Download and install minikube and kubectl</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Estimation  Peril:  How To Estimate  Software Projects Effectively(or How Not To Lie)</title>
      <link>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2017/10/15/estimation-peril-how-to-estimate-software-projects-effectivelyor-how-not-to-lie/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Oct 2017 17:24:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2017/10/15/estimation-peril-how-to-estimate-software-projects-effectivelyor-how-not-to-lie/</guid>
      <description>Consider, you are a rockstar engineer and you are given a task by your favorite person, your project manager, to show some new fields in the dashboard.
As usual, you are asked to estimate it as soon as possible. You think that well, seems like a quickie and you are tempted to estimate it a day. But you, being burnt before, decided to look at the fields that are to be added carefully.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Clean Code Chapter 1&amp;2: Clean Code &amp; Meaningful names</title>
      <link>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2017/08/05/clean-code-chapter-12-clean-code-meaningful-names/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Aug 2017 08:21:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2017/08/05/clean-code-chapter-12-clean-code-meaningful-names/</guid>
      <description>I have started reading the book _Clean Code by Robert C. Martin, _which is considered to be a industry standard for writing maintainable and elegant code.
Because this book is such a heavy read, and each chapter is full of content and a knowledge bank in itself, for personal reference I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to summarise each chapter in a set of blog posts.
Chapter 1 : Clean Code This was more like chapter 0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Philosophy Behind The Offensive Programming</title>
      <link>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2017/07/08/philosophy-behind-the-offensive-programming/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jul 2017 19:30:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2017/07/08/philosophy-behind-the-offensive-programming/</guid>
      <description>Recently I was listening to a podcast and there was this really smart guy Piwai talking about something that instantly captivated by attention. That was the coining of the term Offensive Programming.
What is offensive programming?
Well, you can find the literature on Wikipedia and also I am not the best person to explain that. So check that out please. But fundamentally, _offensive programming _refers to a style of programming that is exact opposite of the more famous counter-part the defensive programming.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Alchemist : Reading Experience</title>
      <link>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2017/05/22/the-alchemist-reading-experience/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 May 2017 18:28:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2017/05/22/the-alchemist-reading-experience/</guid>
      <description>Reading **The Alchemist **was like getting up at dawn and seeing the sun rise, while the whole world slept.
The Alchemist doesn&amp;rsquo;t teach you anything, but you can learn a million things from it.
&amp;ldquo;Lead will play its role until the world has no further need for the lead, and then the lead will have to turn itself into gold.&amp;rdquo;
My 6th book of the year was **The Alchemist **by Paulo Coelho.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Skiffle : Android App To Discover, Search and Explore Music - The Making</title>
      <link>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2017/05/12/skiffle-android-app-to-discover-search-and-explore-music-the-making/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 May 2017 17:48:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2017/05/12/skiffle-android-app-to-discover-search-and-explore-music-the-making/</guid>
      <description>[gallery ids=&amp;ldquo;557,559,558&amp;rdquo; type=&amp;ldquo;rectangular&amp;rdquo;]
This is just a log of contemplate on the challenges and learning I encountered while creating Skiffle : Discover tracks, albums and artists.
Skiffle on GitHub
**Skiffle **was designed with one simple motive , provide fastest way to search for music powered by the best source available. It uses Spotify API as backend.
How this log is structured?
The log is structured under headings. Each heading represents a certain facet of project or technology.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mastery By Robert Greene : Reading Experience</title>
      <link>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2017/04/07/mastery-by-robert-greene-reading-experience/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Apr 2017 20:39:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2017/04/07/mastery-by-robert-greene-reading-experience/</guid>
      <description>“The problem with all students, he said, is that they inevitably stop somewhere. They hear an idea and they hold on to it until it becomes dead; they want to flatter themselves that they know the truth. But true Zen never stops, never congeals into such truths. That is why everyone must constantly be pushed to the abyss, starting over and feeling their utter worthlessness as a student. Without suffering and doubts, the mind will come to rest on clichés and stay there, until the spirit dies as well.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>E-Summit ’17 IIT Bombay — Experience</title>
      <link>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2017/02/03/e-summit-17-iit-bombay%e2%80%8a-%e2%80%8aexperience/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Feb 2017 17:16:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2017/02/03/e-summit-17-iit-bombay%e2%80%8a-%e2%80%8aexperience/</guid>
      <description>E-Summit is the flagship entrepreneurship event organized by IITB. The two-day annual summit promises to be an amazing meeting ground for industry experts, business leaders, investors and entrepreneurs and of course, students, many of whom are aspiring entrepreneurs.
I attended this event in its 2017 edition and had mixed feelings on how the whole thing turned out holistically. There were some good parts and some not so good parts, but as a whole the event was worth attending.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Blue Ocean Strategy : How To Create Uncontested Market Space and Make the Competition Irrelevant</title>
      <link>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2017/01/15/the-blue-ocean-strategy-how-to-create-uncontested-market-space-and-make-the-competition-irrelevant/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Jan 2017 10:49:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2017/01/15/the-blue-ocean-strategy-how-to-create-uncontested-market-space-and-make-the-competition-irrelevant/</guid>
      <description>When Henry Ford made cheap, reliable cars people said, ‘Nah, what’s wrong with a horse?’ That was a huge bet he made, and it worked. The whole idea of _The Blue Ocean Strategy _is to create uncontested market spaces that creates new demands and make the competition irrelevant.
The book describes _Red Oceans _as known market places that have bloody competition among businesses trying to win customers. Here there is a fixed existing demand of which every company wants a share.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning How To Learn : Course Experience</title>
      <link>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2017/01/06/learning-how-to-learn-course-experience/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2017 18:43:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2017/01/06/learning-how-to-learn-course-experience/</guid>
      <description>The human brain has 100 billion neurons, each neuron connected to 10 thousand other neurons. Sitting on your shoulders is the most complicated object in the known universe.
What is learning? Well basically, forming and consolidation neural patterns.
Recently I took the course “Learning How to Learn” on Coursera. I really wanted to figure out the best way to enhance my learning. And this course has been really helpful. It provides you with the right tools and tips to construct your own learning schedule.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zen and the Art of Motorcycle Maintenance : Reading Experience</title>
      <link>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2016/12/25/zen-and-the-art-of-motorcycle-maintenance-reading-experience/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Dec 2016 11:13:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2016/12/25/zen-and-the-art-of-motorcycle-maintenance-reading-experience/</guid>
      <description>The Japanese motorcycle maintenance guide says “ Assembly of Japanese bicycle requires great piece of mind”. There is a thing about everything you build, including bikes. If you build it with non-serene mind, then you build your problems into it.
The book takes you on a cross country bike journey that will teach you mind opening lessons that leave lasting impressions on your mind. Your mind will simple refuse to contract itself to older stage.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>5 notes on MVP architecture pattern for Android</title>
      <link>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2016/12/19/5-notes-on-mvp-architecture-pattern-for-android/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Dec 2016 16:31:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2016/12/19/5-notes-on-mvp-architecture-pattern-for-android/</guid>
      <description>Image credits Macoscope  MVP (Model View and Presenter) is an architectural pattern inspired by the popular MVC pattern.
MVP addresses two main points :
 1. Make views as dumb as possible. The dumber the better. 2. Make each layer loosely coupled and easily testable in isolation.  I am using MVP in one of my production project and have used in some dem0 apps. Here are my 5 notes on using MVP for android.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rise and Shine : How joining the 5 AM club affected my life</title>
      <link>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2016/12/02/rise-and-shine-how-joining-the-5-am-club-affected-my-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Dec 2016 12:10:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2016/12/02/rise-and-shine-how-joining-the-5-am-club-affected-my-life/</guid>
      <description>Being an early riser isn’t about trumpeting how hard you work. It’s about doing everything within your power to help your business achieve success; and if that means you have to get up at an hour not known to most, then you might as well enjoy the sunrise.
It is no secret that many high achievers have been advocating about the importance of waking up early in the morning. I have been following Robin Sharma for quite some time now and he proposes something called as the “5 AM club”.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to detect emails, phone numbers, web URLs, hashtags in Android TextView? : SmartTextView library</title>
      <link>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2016/08/17/how-to-detect-emails-phone-numbers-web-urls-hashtags-in-android-textview-smarttextview-library/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Aug 2016 12:53:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2016/08/17/how-to-detect-emails-phone-numbers-web-urls-hashtags-in-android-textview-smarttextview-library/</guid>
      <description>Smart Text View Star On GitHub Follow On GitHub
Many applications in android use TextView that detects and highlight various string patterns like emails, phone numbers, web URLs and even hashtags.
This functionality is very common and and is used extensively and frequently in many app. Thus to ease the process of adding this functionality I have authored an Android library SmartTextView.
Find and Star it on GitHub : https://github.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IIMBx: EP101x DO Your Venture : Course Experience on edX</title>
      <link>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2016/07/26/iimbx-ep101x-do-your-venture-course-experience-on-edx/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jul 2016 09:57:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2016/07/26/iimbx-ep101x-do-your-venture-course-experience-on-edx/</guid>
      <description>The best way to win is to show grit and bid on your strengths and intuitions. I have been trying to start my own company now for quite a some time. This course came into my mail box by edX, title looked captivating and thus I decided to take it.
It was a light course. Not much effort needed other that just watching the videos and doing some assignments.
The course was focused on making people get off with their venture from the idea phase to execution phase.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Win Friends and Influence People : Reading Experience and Summary</title>
      <link>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2016/07/19/how-to-win-friends-and-influence-people-reading-experience-and-summary/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jul 2016 19:20:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2016/07/19/how-to-win-friends-and-influence-people-reading-experience-and-summary/</guid>
      <description>_How to win friends and influence people _is an all time classic book. I got to know about this book from the _Goodreads _recommendations and instantly decided to read this one. It starts stating that leadership is 15% technical skills and 85% skill to manage human relations. This sentence alone suffices the need of this book.
What you can get out of the book?
 * Gives you new ways to carry on meaningful conversations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Business In Boxers 3 : The Psychological Roller Coaster</title>
      <link>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2016/06/30/business-in-boxers-3-the-psychological-roller-coaster/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jun 2016 18:58:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2016/06/30/business-in-boxers-3-the-psychological-roller-coaster/</guid>
      <description>One of my favorite things about instrumental music is that the listener is encouraged to use his or her imagination. I have been a huge Owl City and Adam Young fan since forever. Lately he is releasing sets of instrumental music called as Adam Young Scores inspired by incidents that made a lasting impression on the world. Reading about all those incidents has made a lasting impression on my mind for sure, our small failures and success doesn&amp;rsquo;t even matter to the world, we have got to make it large.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Marketing Your Retail Store in the Internet Age by Bob Negen  : Reading Experience</title>
      <link>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2016/06/21/marketing-your-retail-store-in-the-internet-age-by-bob-negen-reading-experience/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2016 15:24:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2016/06/21/marketing-your-retail-store-in-the-internet-age-by-bob-negen-reading-experience/</guid>
      <description>This was the book that I knew prior to reading it that it won&amp;rsquo;t be too interesting and might even feel too slow. I searched it on the internet and picked it to read to get a perspective of a retail seller. As me and my team are trying to start a company that will work very closely with retail stores and their owners I thought this book will provide some value.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Sell Your Product or Service by Victor Antonio : Course Experience</title>
      <link>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2016/06/05/how-to-sell-your-product-or-service-by-victor-antonio-course-experience/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jun 2016 17:52:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2016/06/05/how-to-sell-your-product-or-service-by-victor-antonio-course-experience/</guid>
      <description>Every entrepreneur I follow have this strong ability of closing sales. After all if your very nice product doesn&amp;rsquo;t sell, it is not nice.
Sales is also, how you present your company to others. Then let it be market research, approaching concierge customers or VCs, all involves sales thinking.
So, we are planning to make are first market research trip. We are going to meet unknown customers and try to get their views on what we are trying to do.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Business in Boxers 2 : The Rainbow Shelf</title>
      <link>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2016/05/30/business-in-boxers-2-the-rainbow-shelf/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 May 2016 20:12:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2016/05/30/business-in-boxers-2-the-rainbow-shelf/</guid>
      <description>As a 16-17 year old you try to figure out what you want to do with your life and then you just imagine yourself doing that. I am a kind of person who imagines stuff very vividly. Few years down the time river here I am, trying to work as hard as I can in the scorching summer heat on something that I always wanted to do.
Second month working on the startup I always wanted to do.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Lean Startup : Reading Experience</title>
      <link>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2016/03/28/the-lean-startup-reading-experience/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Mar 2016 21:06:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2016/03/28/the-lean-startup-reading-experience/</guid>
      <description>My 3rd book of the year was The Lean Startup by Eric Ries. I first got to know about the existence of this book during a keynote video of Gary Vaynerchuk where it was up for display. Finally got the time to read it.
The book focuses on how the lean manufacturing using in Toyota can be used in startups as well. And it makes sense! The case studies to new terms defined all help you shape your mind to run your startup in a lean manner.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Business in Boxers : 1 Month Into Running a StartUp</title>
      <link>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2016/03/22/business-in-boxers-1-month-into-running-a-startup/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Mar 2016 20:49:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2016/03/22/business-in-boxers-1-month-into-running-a-startup/</guid>
      <description>**Why the Series? **
(Inspired by book : Business In Blue Jeans)
Hi! This is Priyank. This series is about me pen downing my start-up ride. Don&amp;rsquo;t know if it&amp;rsquo;s fast or slow, all I really know is I&amp;rsquo;m gonna enjoy the ride.
Why the name?
Boxers is what you&amp;rsquo;ll find me almost every time in and business is what&amp;rsquo;s always in my mind and thus the name &amp;ldquo;Business In Boxers&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UBCx: Marketing1x Introduction to Marketing : Course Experience</title>
      <link>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2016/02/26/ubcx-marketing1x-introduction-to-marketing-course-experience/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Feb 2016 17:22:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2016/02/26/ubcx-marketing1x-introduction-to-marketing-course-experience/</guid>
      <description>Marketing is no longer about the stuff that you make, but about the stories that you tell.
In today&amp;rsquo;s world everyone in some way or another is trying to market themselves to the world. This becomes even more prominent if you are trying to attract customers to earn your living.
_Preping _to become an entrepreneur, I decided to take this course to get the proper understanding of how the mind of a marketer works.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Couchbase : CB020 and CB140 Experience</title>
      <link>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2016/02/13/couchbase-cb020-and-cb140-experience/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Feb 2016 17:31:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2016/02/13/couchbase-cb020-and-cb140-experience/</guid>
      <description>Last week in one of my project I wanted to store data of a form having more than 100 fields. I knew storing this much scattered info on relational DBs would be tough. Platform being mobile, just made things more complicated. Indications were to use a NoSql DB.
For what I found, Couchbase lite is the best NoSql database for mobile. It is available for both Android and ios platform and thus creating apps for both platforms becomes easy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contagious : Why Things Catch On : Reading Experience</title>
      <link>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2016/02/07/contagious-why-things-catch-on-reading-experience/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Feb 2016 18:29:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2016/02/07/contagious-why-things-catch-on-reading-experience/</guid>
      <description>We all have heard of the hilarious _Panda Cheese _commercial in which a panda screws everyone who says no to panda products. People loved the ad so much that the brand enjoyed world wide recognition. On the other hand commercials by GoldenPalace.com was a complete miss, it just failed to persist their brand name in customer&amp;rsquo;s mind by _Fool in the pool _marketing stunt.
So, what makes things popular? Why do people talk about certain products and ideas more than others?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Losing My Virginity By Richard Branson -  Reading Experience</title>
      <link>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2016/01/19/losing-my-virginity-by-richard-branson-reading-experience/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jan 2016 17:10:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2016/01/19/losing-my-virginity-by-richard-branson-reading-experience/</guid>
      <description>**Oh, screw it, let&#39;s do it.** That&amp;rsquo;s the philosophy of Richard Branson that has allowed him to start ventures in markets that no one dared to enter and even considered ludicrous to try.
Losing my virginity is the most unusual biography you will ever get to read. It looks like you are reading a biography of not a global entrepreneur but an adventurist.
This is the story of how Richard Branson started his entrepreneur journey by starting the Student magazine and strolled his way to opening more than 400 companies under the Virgin brand.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Practice Shapes : Android App To Learn Shapes</title>
      <link>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2015/12/28/practice-shapes-android-app-to-learn-shapes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Dec 2015 14:56:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2015/12/28/practice-shapes-android-app-to-learn-shapes/</guid>
      <description>Only way to learn something is to learn it by yourself. Recently I have been playing with Canvas in android and it has been fun! :D
As they say knowledge is knowing tomato is a fruit. Wisdom is not putting it in vegetable basket. And best way to persist new gained &amp;ldquo;wisdom&amp;rdquo; is to put it in use.
Practice Shapes is a fun app both for kids and grown-up kids (Yes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Edx : Digital Branding and Engagement Course Overview And Experience</title>
      <link>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2015/12/19/edx-digital-branding-and-engagement-course-overview-and-experience/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Dec 2015 09:28:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2015/12/19/edx-digital-branding-and-engagement-course-overview-and-experience/</guid>
      <description>People Respond to Effort Lately I have been following Gary Vaynerchuck, an entrepreneur and serial investor. He also owns a social media marketing company Vayner Media. Listening to his podcasts and keynotes is an eye opener on how digital media marketing is reshaping the advertising world.
So I took a course on Edx Digital Branding and Engagement finally know the digital marketing in and out.
The course was 4 weeks long and delivers perfect contextual content.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Outliers: The Story of Success : Reading Review</title>
      <link>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2015/11/04/outliers-the-story-of-success-reading-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Nov 2015 17:14:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2015/11/04/outliers-the-story-of-success-reading-review/</guid>
      <description>My 6th book of the year was a handpicked one &amp;ldquo;Outliers: The Story of Success&amp;rdquo;. This book was actually recommended to me by my cousin as a &amp;ldquo;must read&amp;rdquo;. And actually I was amazed how great this book is. It takes your intellectual thinking to a roller coaster ride.
As the book description says :
In this stunning new book, Malcolm Gladwell takes us on an intellectual journey through the world of &#34;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Mobile Devices Can Change the Educational Technology and Education?</title>
      <link>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2015/10/20/how-mobile-devices-can-change-the-educational-technology-and-education/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Oct 2015 18:02:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2015/10/20/how-mobile-devices-can-change-the-educational-technology-and-education/</guid>
      <description>Educational technology is growing rapidly and thus is catching everyone&amp;rsquo;s attention. At the same time mobile devices are part of are lives from a long time now. Students and teachers are increasingly embracing tablets and e-book readers in their personal lives.
Accessibility of educational technology is one of the biggest barrier that we are facing. Mobile devices are best way to make this problem less serious.
**Advantages of mobile devices to be used as platform for ed-tech : **</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rails Number Helper Port to Android</title>
      <link>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2015/10/06/rails-number-helper-port-to-android/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2015 14:06:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2015/10/06/rails-number-helper-port-to-android/</guid>
      <description>A polyglot developer will understand, there is always something you like about one language and you wish was available for another language too.
So, recently I started learning rails and found _number_helper _API very cool and fun to use. It gives you easy API to convert numbers into many formats like _number_to_human _which will convert 20000 to _20 Thousands _or number_to_human_size that will convert 1024 to 1 KB.
That was it I wanted this stuff for Android too.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Making GCM client in Android and Application server in Ruby on Rails</title>
      <link>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2015/09/11/making-gcm-client-in-android-and-application-server-in-ruby-on-rails/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Sep 2015 19:17:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2015/09/11/making-gcm-client-in-android-and-application-server-in-ruby-on-rails/</guid>
      <description>It is always fun to play with new APIs and tools. GCM is not something I was getting my hands on for the first time but it changed completely since last time I did a project using this.
But the good news is it has changed for good. New service classes makes it easier to write GCM clients for Android, GCM default configuration makes writing test servers and apps to play with very less tedious.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Paint App in Android</title>
      <link>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2015/09/06/paint-app-in-android/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Sep 2015 10:14:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2015/09/06/paint-app-in-android/</guid>
      <description>Recently I was learning about Canvas and Custom views in Android and to put the theory in practice I made a pretty simple **Paint App. **
Source code of the app can be found https://github.com/priyankvex/Paint-App-Android.
[caption id=&amp;ldquo;attachment_159&amp;rdquo; align=&amp;ldquo;aligncenter&amp;rdquo; width=&amp;ldquo;480&amp;rdquo;] Screenshot of the app[/caption]
The App is pretty simple with features 1. Create Drawings (Obvious one :P). 2. Select different brush sizes. 3. Eraser with different sizes. 4. Color pallet. 5. Save drawings in Gallery.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rafa  : Reading Experience</title>
      <link>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2015/09/05/rafa-reading-experience/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Sep 2015 13:44:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2015/09/05/rafa-reading-experience/</guid>
      <description>Here it is. 4th book of the year Rafa by Rafael Nadal and John Carlin.
Being arguably the biggest Rafa fan on this planet this book was in my reading bucket list from a long time. Finally got the opportunity to read this.
This is great in both sense, it gives you a more closer look into the life of your idol and at the same time shows you what does it take to be a champion?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Making an OCR app for Android using Tesseract.</title>
      <link>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2015/09/02/making-an-ocr-app-for-android-using-tesseract/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Sep 2015 11:01:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2015/09/02/making-an-ocr-app-for-android-using-tesseract/</guid>
      <description>Star on GitHub
Recently I was playing with OCR library by google called as &amp;ldquo;Tesseract&amp;rdquo; (cool name for a library!).
[caption id=&amp;ldquo;attachment_153&amp;rdquo; align=&amp;ldquo;alignleft&amp;rdquo; width=&amp;ldquo;234&amp;rdquo;] App in action.[/caption]
It was a fun experience. This post shows how you can make a simple OCR app in Android using Tesseract.
We will be using Tess-Two a fork of Tesseract with some additional tools like Liptonica which is an image processing library.
If you want an even easier way to get started with OCR on Android you can try this library built by me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MIT 11.133x : Implementation and Evaluation of Educational Technology – Week 4 Sum Up</title>
      <link>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2015/08/30/mit-11-133x-implementation-and-evaluation-of-educational-technology-week-4-sum-up/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Aug 2015 17:28:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2015/08/30/mit-11-133x-implementation-and-evaluation-of-educational-technology-week-4-sum-up/</guid>
      <description>What is the final step after implementation of something? How to assess if something has worked or not? Whether it has achieved the claimed goals or not?
The only proper way to get the answers to the questions like above is by properly _**evaluating **_the implementation. And this is what the final week of the course was all about.
Evaluation is the final frontier that you need to conquer.
Considering Evaluation :</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to build Tesseract OCR library for Android Studio?</title>
      <link>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2015/08/30/how-to-build-tesseract-ocr-library-for-android-studio/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Aug 2015 10:07:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2015/08/30/how-to-build-tesseract-ocr-library-for-android-studio/</guid>
      <description>Star On GitHub
If you ever tried to create an OCR app for Android you must have stumbled upon the OCR library by Google Tesseract. And then the problems began.
To use the library in your project you first need to build it. But building the library to be compatible with gradle, which is the new build system for Android projects is little not so easily stated anywhere in the library manual.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MIT 11.133x : Implementation and Evaluation of Educational Technology – Week 3 Sum Up</title>
      <link>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2015/08/23/mit-11-133x-implementation-and-evaluation-of-educational-technology-week-3-sum-up/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Aug 2015 18:15:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2015/08/23/mit-11-133x-implementation-and-evaluation-of-educational-technology-week-3-sum-up/</guid>
      <description>What does it take to implement a educational technology? You have the idea that can supposedly change the world of ed tech and learning, but how to implement it?
Throughout the course, in the past 3 weeks I was constantly having my idea of creating an ed tech. With each passing week the course taught me something new which can be used to carve the idea even better.
By the end of 3 weeks I was having a very clear vision of what area of learning I have to target in my ed tech implementation, but again no technical knowledge was there on how to shape up the implementation wire-frame.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MIT 11.133x : Implementation and Evaluation of Educational Technology – Week 2 Sum Up</title>
      <link>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2015/08/04/mit-11-133x-implementation-and-evaluation-of-educational-technology-week-2-sum-up/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Aug 2015 17:21:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2015/08/04/mit-11-133x-implementation-and-evaluation-of-educational-technology-week-2-sum-up/</guid>
      <description>Here is it end of week 2 of 11.133x. And we are back with the sum up.
This week was about many aspects that one should deal with while implementing an education technology, like deciding education technology framework, how to analyse a ed tech, technology buying process etc.
This week started with TPACK. What is TPACK and why does it matter?
TPACK is a framework which combines 3 knowledge. These are technological knowledge, content knowledge and pedagogical knowledge.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MIT 11.133x : Implementation and Evaluation of Educational Technology – Week 1 Sum Up</title>
      <link>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2015/07/26/mit-11-133x-implementation-and-evaluation-of-educational-technology-week-1-sum-up/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jul 2015 18:51:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2015/07/26/mit-11-133x-implementation-and-evaluation-of-educational-technology-week-1-sum-up/</guid>
      <description>Here is it. End of week 1 of the course 11.133x.
This week was a little more focused on educational technology. It covered various vital topics like :
 1. Stakeholders in ed tech. 2. Evaluation and assessment. 3. What makes a good ed tech? 4. Future of teaching. 5. Where to start with ed tech? 6. Concept of SAMR.  **Stakeholders in Ed Tech : **
Stakeholders in ed tech are the ones who are going to be affected by the ed tech the most.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Passionate Programmer : Reading Experience</title>
      <link>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2015/07/22/the-passionate-programmer-reading-experience/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jul 2015 17:36:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2015/07/22/the-passionate-programmer-reading-experience/</guid>
      <description>Here we go for the 3rd time. My 3rd book for 2015&amp;rsquo;s 10 book reading challenge is _The Passionate Programmer. _
I picked this book from pragmatic programmer book shelf. All books listed there are awesome and are a must read. Anyways continuing with this book, it was an awesome reading experience. It was one of those books you wish to never end.
The author covers many aspects of what constitutes a not good but a great software developing career.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MIT 11.133x  : Implementation and Evaluation of Educational Technology - Week 0 Sum Up</title>
      <link>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2015/07/19/mit-11-133x-implementation-and-evaluation-of-educational-technology-week-0-sum-up/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jul 2015 05:15:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2015/07/19/mit-11-133x-implementation-and-evaluation-of-educational-technology-week-0-sum-up/</guid>
      <description>This week I started with another MOOC by Edx &amp;ldquo;Implementation and Evaluation of Educational Technology&amp;rdquo;. It is a 5 weeks course going from week 0 to week 4.
So here I will blog about my experiences with the course, each week.
WEEK 0
There was not much in the course in week 0. You can guess that by week number.
Week started with introduction to forums and edx platform and how we are supposed to proceed with the course.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Agile For Dummies : Reading experience</title>
      <link>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2015/06/27/agile-for-dummies-reading-experience/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jun 2015 04:42:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2015/06/27/agile-for-dummies-reading-experience/</guid>
      <description>Agile For Dummies
Here we go for the 2nd time. My 2nd book for 2015&amp;rsquo;s 10 book reading challenge is Agile For Dummies.
As I wrote in my previous post I am going to avoid fiction and love stories, but focus more on technical and personal improvement books.
By the time I wrote this post I was in Bangalore for software engineer internship at HealthGraph India. There we were using agile methodology (scrum) for our project.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Pragmatic Programmer: From Journeyman to Master :  Reading Experience</title>
      <link>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2015/06/20/the-pragmatic-programmer-from-journeyman-to-master/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jun 2015 07:47:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2015/06/20/the-pragmatic-programmer-from-journeyman-to-master/</guid>
      <description>The Pragmatic Programmer
From this day forth, I have decided to develop my love for reading. I have made a reading goal of minimum 10 books a year, including technical and non technical books. Majority of them are going to be technical but I will get my hands to some non technical ones too. I am going to avoid love stories and pure fiction ones.
Okay, the reason for this much rambling on the net?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>5 Coolest features of Android Studio</title>
      <link>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2015/01/26/5-coolest-features-of-android-studio/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2015 20:24:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2015/01/26/5-coolest-features-of-android-studio/</guid>
      <description>Android Studio is out and stable now. It is always fun to try new tools. Right?
So far it has been around 2 months since I have been using Android Studio. And I guess it is the best time to select my personal choice of 5 coolest features of it.
If you want some technical or geeky feature list RTFM! This post is not meant for that.
1. Code preview scrolling</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>10 Things I want to do before I graduate.</title>
      <link>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2014/10/01/10-things-i-want-to-do-before-i-graduate/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2014 18:21:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2014/10/01/10-things-i-want-to-do-before-i-graduate/</guid>
      <description>I am almost half an engineer by this time. Two and a half year and I will be a graduate. Sounds like fun. So I guess this is the best time to reveal 10 things I want to do before I die . Oh! sorry, before I graduate.
1. Google Summer Of Code Okay. First one should not be a surprise for computer students. Gsoc is like a dream for almost every computer engineering student.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>6.00.1x: Introduction to Computer Science and Programming Using Python : The Experience</title>
      <link>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2014/09/20/6-00-1x-introduction-to-computer-science-and-programming-using-python-the-experience/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Sep 2014 03:09:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2014/09/20/6-00-1x-introduction-to-computer-science-and-programming-using-python-the-experience/</guid>
      <description>Hi, guys. I am a very active participant of MOOC. In my previous post I shared my experience with LFS101x : Introduction to linux .And this time I am back with a new course.
It was summer of 2014, I was having my semester break. And 6.00.1x was on my enrollment list on edx. I was really excited to get started with it.
As this course says, it is meant for people with little to no programming experience, I was there having some programming experience but quiet a novice to python.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LFS101x : Introduction to Linux on edX</title>
      <link>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2014/08/16/lfs101x-introduction-to-linux-on-edx/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Aug 2014 10:13:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2014/08/16/lfs101x-introduction-to-linux-on-edx/</guid>
      <description>It was this summer when I saw this course LFS101x being offered on edX by The Linux Foundation. Both the terms Linux and edX excited me . So I decided to take this course.
My experience with prior online courses I have taken few online courses on edX and coursera . In both the cases I loved the excitement and knowledge they provide. They were also fun learning and thus worked well for me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What to do? An android app made to guide people what to do in various scenarios.</title>
      <link>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2014/06/27/what-to-do-an-android-app-made-to-guide-people-what-to-do-in-various-scenarios/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jun 2014 08:02:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2014/06/27/what-to-do-an-android-app-made-to-guide-people-what-to-do-in-various-scenarios/</guid>
      <description>Click Here to download  _NOTE : _This app has been signed with default debug key
We all face various scenarios in our life . Some are life threatening while some are just awkward moments . In each case it is kinda vital to do the write things at the write time . This app has been made to help you do the same with the help researched content and quick links provided within the app.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Android Application for a basic Calculator.</title>
      <link>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2014/06/04/android-application-for-a-basic-calculator/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jun 2014 19:35:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2014/06/04/android-application-for-a-basic-calculator/</guid>
      <description>Hi there,
This time would like to share my new project &amp;lsquo; A basic calculator built for the android platform.&amp;rsquo;
Creating android apps always seemed cool to me . Able to start learning to create one is even cooler.
This project uses simple things like XML layouts, Activities using java, Intents, OnclickListeners and some more basic concepts of java and android.
Below are the screenshots of the app running in both real android device and AVD.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Basic Calculator using Swing and JAVA(TM).</title>
      <link>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2014/05/22/a-basic-calculator-using-swing-and-javatm/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 May 2014 17:34:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2014/05/22/a-basic-calculator-using-swing-and-javatm/</guid>
      <description>Hi,there . This time i would like to share my new work. This a basic four function calculator made using java and Swing. The GUI created is with the help of&amp;hellip;.you guessed it right SWING.

Java simple calculator
 A four-function calculator with the following functions: Addition – adds two numbers Subtraction – subtracts number two from number one Multiplication – Multiplies two numbers Division – divides number two into number one</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>STAR WARS ENCYCLOPEDIA: A layout implementation using HTML5 and CSS3</title>
      <link>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2014/05/08/star-wars-encyclopedia-a-layout-implementation-using-html5-and-css3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 May 2014 19:46:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2014/05/08/star-wars-encyclopedia-a-layout-implementation-using-html5-and-css3/</guid>
      <description>STAR WARS Encyclopedia Hi, there. Before we go further, if you are a STAR WARS fan like me you are going to love this one. This time i would love to share my another layout creation using HTML5 and CSS3 only. And the most interesting part, this effort was dedicated to STAR WARS.
The Wire Frame [caption id=&amp;ldquo;attachment_46&amp;rdquo; align=&amp;ldquo;aligncenter&amp;rdquo; width=&amp;ldquo;132&amp;rdquo;] Wire frame of the web page.[/caption]
After creating the aire frame, the next step was to make things really come to life in the photoshop.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>House Of Horrors : A responsive web design</title>
      <link>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2014/05/06/house-of-horrors-a-responsive-web-design/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 May 2014 15:54:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2014/05/06/house-of-horrors-a-responsive-web-design/</guid>
      <description>Hi there. This post is to share my experience and work under getting started with &amp;lsquo;Responsive web design&amp;rsquo;. I created a website under the theme of House Of Horrors, and I am not even leaving my desk and posting this right away. Any suggestions are more then welcome!.As it was a project under &amp;lsquo;Responsive Web design&amp;rsquo;, so firstly what i did was, i created 3 wire frames of the website as high resolution, medium resolution and low resolution.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Newton-Raphson vs Bisection Search vs Brute force for finding square root of  number.</title>
      <link>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2014/04/01/newton-raphson-vs-bisection-search-vs-brute-force-for-finding-square-root-of-number/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2014 06:28:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2014/04/01/newton-raphson-vs-bisection-search-vs-brute-force-for-finding-square-root-of-number/</guid>
      <description>Computers are meant to compute things. Finding square root is a very basic algorithm which can be coded in basically 3 ways : All 3 ways are based on the _Guess and check method _ A.K.A Exhaustive Enumeration. _ &amp;gt;1. Brute force method :_
__ In this method we test all the possible values and test them .
_2. Bisection Search : _
By cutting the problem into the half after every iteration.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Starting c/c&#43;&#43; programming in Linux.</title>
      <link>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2014/03/11/starting-cc-programming-in-linux/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2014 19:04:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2014/03/11/starting-cc-programming-in-linux/</guid>
      <description>So, guys this post is just a kick off to my blog.
This post is about coding in c or c++ in Linux . So, if you are a beginner looking to get your hand on coding in c or c++ in Linux, this will be of great help.
STEPS:
1.You can use gedit or i recommend you download Sublime Text for Linux.
 Select your language as c/c++ and code and save the file.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>