<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>experience on Erlich Bachman</title>
    <link>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/tags/experience/</link>
    <description>Recent content in experience on Erlich Bachman</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 02 Sep 2018 17:42:58 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/tags/experience/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>A plea for lean software: 6 Lessons I learned to help keep software simple</title>
      <link>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2018/09/02/a-plea-for-lean-software-6-lessons-i-learned-to-help-keep-software-simple/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Sep 2018 17:42:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2018/09/02/a-plea-for-lean-software-6-lessons-i-learned-to-help-keep-software-simple/</guid>
      <description>Preface Recently, I was browsing the codebase of my company and saw that it has three versions of dashboards for an analytics page in it. I am pretty sure that customers don&amp;rsquo;t need that. This sparked something in my naive brain and I started exploring the internet for related ideas. That&amp;rsquo;s when I found this age-old paper, A Plea for Lean Software.
This post is largely influenced by ideas presented in the paper that resonated with me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>E-Summit ’17 IIT Bombay — Experience</title>
      <link>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2017/02/03/e-summit-17-iit-bombay%e2%80%8a-%e2%80%8aexperience/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Feb 2017 17:16:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2017/02/03/e-summit-17-iit-bombay%e2%80%8a-%e2%80%8aexperience/</guid>
      <description>E-Summit is the flagship entrepreneurship event organized by IITB. The two-day annual summit promises to be an amazing meeting ground for industry experts, business leaders, investors and entrepreneurs and of course, students, many of whom are aspiring entrepreneurs.
I attended this event in its 2017 edition and had mixed feelings on how the whole thing turned out holistically. There were some good parts and some not so good parts, but as a whole the event was worth attending.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning How To Learn : Course Experience</title>
      <link>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2017/01/06/learning-how-to-learn-course-experience/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2017 18:43:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2017/01/06/learning-how-to-learn-course-experience/</guid>
      <description>The human brain has 100 billion neurons, each neuron connected to 10 thousand other neurons. Sitting on your shoulders is the most complicated object in the known universe.
What is learning? Well basically, forming and consolidation neural patterns.
Recently I took the course “Learning How to Learn” on Coursera. I really wanted to figure out the best way to enhance my learning. And this course has been really helpful. It provides you with the right tools and tips to construct your own learning schedule.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zen and the Art of Motorcycle Maintenance : Reading Experience</title>
      <link>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2016/12/25/zen-and-the-art-of-motorcycle-maintenance-reading-experience/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Dec 2016 11:13:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2016/12/25/zen-and-the-art-of-motorcycle-maintenance-reading-experience/</guid>
      <description>The Japanese motorcycle maintenance guide says “ Assembly of Japanese bicycle requires great piece of mind”. There is a thing about everything you build, including bikes. If you build it with non-serene mind, then you build your problems into it.
The book takes you on a cross country bike journey that will teach you mind opening lessons that leave lasting impressions on your mind. Your mind will simple refuse to contract itself to older stage.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IIMBx: EP101x DO Your Venture : Course Experience on edX</title>
      <link>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2016/07/26/iimbx-ep101x-do-your-venture-course-experience-on-edx/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jul 2016 09:57:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2016/07/26/iimbx-ep101x-do-your-venture-course-experience-on-edx/</guid>
      <description>The best way to win is to show grit and bid on your strengths and intuitions. I have been trying to start my own company now for quite a some time. This course came into my mail box by edX, title looked captivating and thus I decided to take it.
It was a light course. Not much effort needed other that just watching the videos and doing some assignments.
The course was focused on making people get off with their venture from the idea phase to execution phase.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Win Friends and Influence People : Reading Experience and Summary</title>
      <link>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2016/07/19/how-to-win-friends-and-influence-people-reading-experience-and-summary/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jul 2016 19:20:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2016/07/19/how-to-win-friends-and-influence-people-reading-experience-and-summary/</guid>
      <description>_How to win friends and influence people _is an all time classic book. I got to know about this book from the _Goodreads _recommendations and instantly decided to read this one. It starts stating that leadership is 15% technical skills and 85% skill to manage human relations. This sentence alone suffices the need of this book.
What you can get out of the book?
 * Gives you new ways to carry on meaningful conversations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Business In Boxers 3 : The Psychological Roller Coaster</title>
      <link>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2016/06/30/business-in-boxers-3-the-psychological-roller-coaster/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jun 2016 18:58:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2016/06/30/business-in-boxers-3-the-psychological-roller-coaster/</guid>
      <description>One of my favorite things about instrumental music is that the listener is encouraged to use his or her imagination. I have been a huge Owl City and Adam Young fan since forever. Lately he is releasing sets of instrumental music called as Adam Young Scores inspired by incidents that made a lasting impression on the world. Reading about all those incidents has made a lasting impression on my mind for sure, our small failures and success doesn&amp;rsquo;t even matter to the world, we have got to make it large.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Marketing Your Retail Store in the Internet Age by Bob Negen  : Reading Experience</title>
      <link>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2016/06/21/marketing-your-retail-store-in-the-internet-age-by-bob-negen-reading-experience/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2016 15:24:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2016/06/21/marketing-your-retail-store-in-the-internet-age-by-bob-negen-reading-experience/</guid>
      <description>This was the book that I knew prior to reading it that it won&amp;rsquo;t be too interesting and might even feel too slow. I searched it on the internet and picked it to read to get a perspective of a retail seller. As me and my team are trying to start a company that will work very closely with retail stores and their owners I thought this book will provide some value.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Business in Boxers : 1 Month Into Running a StartUp</title>
      <link>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2016/03/22/business-in-boxers-1-month-into-running-a-startup/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Mar 2016 20:49:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2016/03/22/business-in-boxers-1-month-into-running-a-startup/</guid>
      <description>**Why the Series? **
(Inspired by book : Business In Blue Jeans)
Hi! This is Priyank. This series is about me pen downing my start-up ride. Don&amp;rsquo;t know if it&amp;rsquo;s fast or slow, all I really know is I&amp;rsquo;m gonna enjoy the ride.
Why the name?
Boxers is what you&amp;rsquo;ll find me almost every time in and business is what&amp;rsquo;s always in my mind and thus the name &amp;ldquo;Business In Boxers&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UBCx: Marketing1x Introduction to Marketing : Course Experience</title>
      <link>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2016/02/26/ubcx-marketing1x-introduction-to-marketing-course-experience/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Feb 2016 17:22:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2016/02/26/ubcx-marketing1x-introduction-to-marketing-course-experience/</guid>
      <description>Marketing is no longer about the stuff that you make, but about the stories that you tell.
In today&amp;rsquo;s world everyone in some way or another is trying to market themselves to the world. This becomes even more prominent if you are trying to attract customers to earn your living.
_Preping _to become an entrepreneur, I decided to take this course to get the proper understanding of how the mind of a marketer works.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contagious : Why Things Catch On : Reading Experience</title>
      <link>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2016/02/07/contagious-why-things-catch-on-reading-experience/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Feb 2016 18:29:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2016/02/07/contagious-why-things-catch-on-reading-experience/</guid>
      <description>We all have heard of the hilarious _Panda Cheese _commercial in which a panda screws everyone who says no to panda products. People loved the ad so much that the brand enjoyed world wide recognition. On the other hand commercials by GoldenPalace.com was a complete miss, it just failed to persist their brand name in customer&amp;rsquo;s mind by _Fool in the pool _marketing stunt.
So, what makes things popular? Why do people talk about certain products and ideas more than others?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Edx : Digital Branding and Engagement Course Overview And Experience</title>
      <link>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2015/12/19/edx-digital-branding-and-engagement-course-overview-and-experience/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Dec 2015 09:28:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2015/12/19/edx-digital-branding-and-engagement-course-overview-and-experience/</guid>
      <description>People Respond to Effort Lately I have been following Gary Vaynerchuck, an entrepreneur and serial investor. He also owns a social media marketing company Vayner Media. Listening to his podcasts and keynotes is an eye opener on how digital media marketing is reshaping the advertising world.
So I took a course on Edx Digital Branding and Engagement finally know the digital marketing in and out.
The course was 4 weeks long and delivers perfect contextual content.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rafa  : Reading Experience</title>
      <link>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2015/09/05/rafa-reading-experience/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Sep 2015 13:44:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2015/09/05/rafa-reading-experience/</guid>
      <description>Here it is. 4th book of the year Rafa by Rafael Nadal and John Carlin.
Being arguably the biggest Rafa fan on this planet this book was in my reading bucket list from a long time. Finally got the opportunity to read this.
This is great in both sense, it gives you a more closer look into the life of your idol and at the same time shows you what does it take to be a champion?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>6.00.1x: Introduction to Computer Science and Programming Using Python : The Experience</title>
      <link>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2014/09/20/6-00-1x-introduction-to-computer-science-and-programming-using-python-the-experience/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Sep 2014 03:09:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2014/09/20/6-00-1x-introduction-to-computer-science-and-programming-using-python-the-experience/</guid>
      <description>Hi, guys. I am a very active participant of MOOC. In my previous post I shared my experience with LFS101x : Introduction to linux .And this time I am back with a new course.
It was summer of 2014, I was having my semester break. And 6.00.1x was on my enrollment list on edx. I was really excited to get started with it.
As this course says, it is meant for people with little to no programming experience, I was there having some programming experience but quiet a novice to python.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>