<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>paper on Steam - a minimal theme for Hugo</title>
    <link>https://example.org/tags/paper/</link>
    <description>Recent content in paper on Steam - a minimal theme for Hugo</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 02 Sep 2018 17:42:58 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://example.org/tags/paper/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>A plea for lean software: 6 Lessons I learned to help keep software simple</title>
      <link>https://example.org/2018/09/02/a-plea-for-lean-software-6-lessons-i-learned-to-help-keep-software-simple/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Sep 2018 17:42:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.org/2018/09/02/a-plea-for-lean-software-6-lessons-i-learned-to-help-keep-software-simple/</guid>
      <description>Preface Recently, I was browsing the codebase of my company and saw that it has three versions of dashboards for an analytics page in it. I am pretty sure that customers don&amp;rsquo;t need that. This sparked something in my naive brain and I started exploring the internet for related ideas. That&amp;rsquo;s when I found this age-old paper, A Plea for Lean Software.
This post is largely influenced by ideas presented in the paper that resonated with me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Acceptance Tests: The Best Medium of Communication Between Stakeholders (if done right)</title>
      <link>https://example.org/2018/08/06/acceptance-tests-the-best-medium-of-communication-between-stakeholders-if-done-right/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Aug 2018 18:41:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.org/2018/08/06/acceptance-tests-the-best-medium-of-communication-between-stakeholders-if-done-right/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s a nice pleasant morning, and you have just entered the office. You greet your friends and grab a cup of coffee. You check your email and there is a new story assigned to you.
&amp;ldquo;As a customer, I get my usage logs backed up&amp;rdquo;
This is where is fun begins.
Communicating Requirements A product engineer&amp;rsquo;s job is to have effective and clear communication as much as it is to write code.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Devops and The Principle Of Flow</title>
      <link>https://example.org/2018/04/29/devops-and-the-principle-of-lean/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Apr 2018 17:01:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.org/2018/04/29/devops-and-the-principle-of-lean/</guid>
      <description>In the technology value stream, work typically flows from Development to Operations, steps consisting of functional areas between our business and our customers.
As stated in the lean principles developed by Toyota, we should optimize to get a single-piece fast and smooth flow for our releases.
We increase flow by:
 1. Making work visible, 2. Reducing batch sizes and intervals of work 3. Building in the quality, preventing defects from being passed to downstream work centers.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>