<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>ideas on Priyank Verma</title>
    <link>https://priyankvex.github.io/PriyankVermaBlogGenerated/tags/ideas/</link>
    <description>Recent content in ideas on Priyank Verma</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 02 Sep 2018 17:42:58 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://priyankvex.github.io/PriyankVermaBlogGenerated/tags/ideas/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>A plea for lean software: 6 Lessons I learned to help keep software simple</title>
      <link>https://priyankvex.github.io/PriyankVermaBlogGenerated/2018/09/02/a-plea-for-lean-software-6-lessons-i-learned-to-help-keep-software-simple/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Sep 2018 17:42:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://priyankvex.github.io/PriyankVermaBlogGenerated/2018/09/02/a-plea-for-lean-software-6-lessons-i-learned-to-help-keep-software-simple/</guid>
      <description>Preface Recently, I was browsing the codebase of my company and saw that it has three versions of dashboards for an analytics page in it. I am pretty sure that customers don&amp;rsquo;t need that. This sparked something in my naive brain and I started exploring the internet for related ideas. That&amp;rsquo;s when I found this age-old paper, A Plea for Lean Software.
This post is largely influenced by ideas presented in the paper that resonated with me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>6 Lessons On Work Ethic I Learned In One Year Of Professional Career</title>
      <link>https://priyankvex.github.io/PriyankVermaBlogGenerated/2018/07/21/6-lessons-on-work-ethic-i-learned-in-one-year-of-professional-career/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Jul 2018 18:17:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://priyankvex.github.io/PriyankVermaBlogGenerated/2018/07/21/6-lessons-on-work-ethic-i-learned-in-one-year-of-professional-career/</guid>
      <description>Time flies. Recently I had completed one year as a full-time employee at my current employer **Squad. **A year has passed, and I decided it was time to revisit instances, memories, and experiences and to recollect what I had learned as a professional in this past year.
It was also a wake-up call to reassess and redirect the ship named professional career to make sure it doesn&amp;rsquo;t get stuck in a whirlpool.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Practical Problem Solving Framework: Inspired By The Toyota Way</title>
      <link>https://priyankvex.github.io/PriyankVermaBlogGenerated/2018/03/25/practical-problem-solving-framework-inspired-by-the-toyota-way/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Mar 2018 11:32:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://priyankvex.github.io/PriyankVermaBlogGenerated/2018/03/25/practical-problem-solving-framework-inspired-by-the-toyota-way/</guid>
      <description>We all will agree to a certain point that having a system/process for anything reduces chances of errors.
As an engineer or someone people look forward to propose solutions to problems it&amp;rsquo;s beneficial to have a framework in place to solve problems effectively.
Recently I was reading _**The Toyota Way, **_and it suggested a framework to _Practical Problem Solving. _It almost felt trivial that this sort of framework would be invaluable to software engineers too (in fact for everyone).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2018, New Year: Let&#39;s Set The Rhythm For What Lies Ahead</title>
      <link>https://priyankvex.github.io/PriyankVermaBlogGenerated/2018/01/01/2018-new-year-lets-set-the-rhythm-for-what-lies-ahead/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2017 19:35:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://priyankvex.github.io/PriyankVermaBlogGenerated/2018/01/01/2018-new-year-lets-set-the-rhythm-for-what-lies-ahead/</guid>
      <description>Here are the 9 things I would love to incorporate into my life as I set myself to see the sun of 2018.
1. Stop chasing the long dream, start conquering the micro-goals: Start cultivating a passionate dedication to the pursuit of short-term goals, being micro ambitious. Putting my head down and work with pride, whatever is the job in the hand. If we see too far in front of us, we won&amp;rsquo;t see shiny thing right in front of us.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>