<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>to on Erlich Bachman</title>
    <link>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/tags/to/</link>
    <description>Recent content in to on Erlich Bachman</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 02 Sep 2018 17:42:58 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/tags/to/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>A plea for lean software: 6 Lessons I learned to help keep software simple</title>
      <link>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2018/09/02/a-plea-for-lean-software-6-lessons-i-learned-to-help-keep-software-simple/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Sep 2018 17:42:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2018/09/02/a-plea-for-lean-software-6-lessons-i-learned-to-help-keep-software-simple/</guid>
      <description>Preface Recently, I was browsing the codebase of my company and saw that it has three versions of dashboards for an analytics page in it. I am pretty sure that customers don&amp;rsquo;t need that. This sparked something in my naive brain and I started exploring the internet for related ideas. That&amp;rsquo;s when I found this age-old paper, A Plea for Lean Software.
This post is largely influenced by ideas presented in the paper that resonated with me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Acceptance Tests: The Best Medium of Communication Between Stakeholders (if done right)</title>
      <link>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2018/08/06/acceptance-tests-the-best-medium-of-communication-between-stakeholders-if-done-right/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Aug 2018 18:41:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2018/08/06/acceptance-tests-the-best-medium-of-communication-between-stakeholders-if-done-right/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s a nice pleasant morning, and you have just entered the office. You greet your friends and grab a cup of coffee. You check your email and there is a new story assigned to you.
&amp;ldquo;As a customer, I get my usage logs backed up&amp;rdquo;
This is where is fun begins.
Communicating Requirements A product engineer&amp;rsquo;s job is to have effective and clear communication as much as it is to write code.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>6 Lessons On Work Ethic I Learned In One Year Of Professional Career</title>
      <link>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2018/07/21/6-lessons-on-work-ethic-i-learned-in-one-year-of-professional-career/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Jul 2018 18:17:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2018/07/21/6-lessons-on-work-ethic-i-learned-in-one-year-of-professional-career/</guid>
      <description>Time flies. Recently I had completed one year as a full-time employee at my current employer **Squad. **A year has passed, and I decided it was time to revisit instances, memories, and experiences and to recollect what I had learned as a professional in this past year.
It was also a wake-up call to reassess and redirect the ship named professional career to make sure it doesn&amp;rsquo;t get stuck in a whirlpool.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tracking Metrics to Surface and Solve Problems: Metric Tracking Practices I&#39;ve Learned So Far</title>
      <link>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2018/05/21/tracking-metrics-to-surface-and-solve-problems-metric-tracking-practices-ive-learned-so-far/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 May 2018 20:11:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2018/05/21/tracking-metrics-to-surface-and-solve-problems-metric-tracking-practices-ive-learned-so-far/</guid>
      <description>It is a nice pleasant evening, you are sipping coffee and reviewing your code one final time, just so that you can gather enough confidence to hit the deploy button.
But a fact of life as a software engineer is that things can go wrong. Small changes may result in unexpected outcomes, including outages, errors or negatively impacting customers.
And when problems occur, either we can do random checks and validations that may or may not solve the problem or we can have a disciplined problem-solving approach that relies on data rather than intuitions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Organization Archetypes And The Concept Of Market-Oriented &#34;Solver Teams&#34;</title>
      <link>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2018/05/05/organization-archetypes-and-the-concept-of-market-oriented-solver-teams/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 May 2018 15:56:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2018/05/05/organization-archetypes-and-the-concept-of-market-oriented-solver-teams/</guid>
      <description>Organizations which designs systems are constrained to produce designs which are copies of the communication structure of the organization.
In other words, how we organize our teams has a powerful effect on the software we produce, as well as our resulting architectural and production outcomes.
Thus, in order to get a fast flow of work from Development to Operations, with high quality, great customer outcomes and fast speed of delivery, we must organize our teams to bring the team structure to our advantage.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Devops and The Principle Of Flow</title>
      <link>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2018/04/29/devops-and-the-principle-of-lean/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Apr 2018 17:01:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2018/04/29/devops-and-the-principle-of-lean/</guid>
      <description>In the technology value stream, work typically flows from Development to Operations, steps consisting of functional areas between our business and our customers.
As stated in the lean principles developed by Toyota, we should optimize to get a single-piece fast and smooth flow for our releases.
We increase flow by:
 1. Making work visible, 2. Reducing batch sizes and intervals of work 3. Building in the quality, preventing defects from being passed to downstream work centers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>7 Tips On Making Your Engineering Workflow Faster</title>
      <link>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2018/04/23/7-tips-on-making-your-engineering-workflow-faster/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Apr 2018 19:55:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2018/04/23/7-tips-on-making-your-engineering-workflow-faster/</guid>
      <description>One of the most important thing that I like about pair programming with other awesome engineers is you get to see their workflows. How they get things done? How they get find and make their way around tools, terminal, and editors?
After witnessing and getting awestruck by many such experiences I realized that having an effective workflow can increase your day to productivity many folds.
The next step was to take action, and while doing so, I have compiled few tips to make your engineering flow faster too.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fail Fast: Hone Your Ability to Recover and Respond Quickly</title>
      <link>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2018/04/14/fail-fast-hone-your-ability-to-recover-and-respond-quickly/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Apr 2018 18:16:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2018/04/14/fail-fast-hone-your-ability-to-recover-and-respond-quickly/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s close to midnight and you are about to wrap your day off. Suddenly you get a pager-duty to resolve a critical bug that&amp;rsquo;s failing some of the automated reporting emails.
You go on to check the logs in the log management tool. This is not the ideal time to find out that logs are not getting streamed to the log management service properly.
Next, you decide to check the performance metrics of the email API and you realize that you don&amp;rsquo;t know the new monitoring tool well enough to get the right metrics quickly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Strive to learn : 8 Ways to optimize for learning at work as a software engineer</title>
      <link>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2018/04/07/strive-to-learn-8-ways-to-optimize-for-learning-at-work-as-software-engineer/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Apr 2018 15:30:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2018/04/07/strive-to-learn-8-ways-to-optimize-for-learning-at-work-as-software-engineer/</guid>
      <description>A large open space with amazing ergonomic chairs where people discuss and execute upon disrupting ideas. It&amp;rsquo;s right next to company&amp;rsquo;s game room where you unwind after a hard work day. Here is we as engineers, get to work on products that our customers love and we love delivering that delight by continuous delivery (or something else :P).
Yet the most prominent thing that excites and should excite an effective engineer is the opportunity for learning at work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Estimation  Peril:  How To Estimate  Software Projects Effectively(or How Not To Lie)</title>
      <link>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2017/10/15/estimation-peril-how-to-estimate-software-projects-effectivelyor-how-not-to-lie/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Oct 2017 17:24:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2017/10/15/estimation-peril-how-to-estimate-software-projects-effectivelyor-how-not-to-lie/</guid>
      <description>Consider, you are a rockstar engineer and you are given a task by your favorite person, your project manager, to show some new fields in the dashboard.
As usual, you are asked to estimate it as soon as possible. You think that well, seems like a quickie and you are tempted to estimate it a day. But you, being burnt before, decided to look at the fields that are to be added carefully.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning How To Learn : Course Experience</title>
      <link>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2017/01/06/learning-how-to-learn-course-experience/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2017 18:43:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2017/01/06/learning-how-to-learn-course-experience/</guid>
      <description>The human brain has 100 billion neurons, each neuron connected to 10 thousand other neurons. Sitting on your shoulders is the most complicated object in the known universe.
What is learning? Well basically, forming and consolidation neural patterns.
Recently I took the course “Learning How to Learn” on Coursera. I really wanted to figure out the best way to enhance my learning. And this course has been really helpful. It provides you with the right tools and tips to construct your own learning schedule.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>5 notes on MVP architecture pattern for Android</title>
      <link>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2016/12/19/5-notes-on-mvp-architecture-pattern-for-android/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Dec 2016 16:31:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2016/12/19/5-notes-on-mvp-architecture-pattern-for-android/</guid>
      <description>Image credits Macoscope  MVP (Model View and Presenter) is an architectural pattern inspired by the popular MVC pattern.
MVP addresses two main points :
 1. Make views as dumb as possible. The dumber the better. 2. Make each layer loosely coupled and easily testable in isolation.  I am using MVP in one of my production project and have used in some dem0 apps. Here are my 5 notes on using MVP for android.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Win Friends and Influence People : Reading Experience and Summary</title>
      <link>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2016/07/19/how-to-win-friends-and-influence-people-reading-experience-and-summary/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jul 2016 19:20:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2016/07/19/how-to-win-friends-and-influence-people-reading-experience-and-summary/</guid>
      <description>_How to win friends and influence people _is an all time classic book. I got to know about this book from the _Goodreads _recommendations and instantly decided to read this one. It starts stating that leadership is 15% technical skills and 85% skill to manage human relations. This sentence alone suffices the need of this book.
What you can get out of the book?
 * Gives you new ways to carry on meaningful conversations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>10 Things I want to do before I graduate.</title>
      <link>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2014/10/01/10-things-i-want-to-do-before-i-graduate/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2014 18:21:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shenoybr.github.io/hugo-goa-demo/2014/10/01/10-things-i-want-to-do-before-i-graduate/</guid>
      <description>I am almost half an engineer by this time. Two and a half year and I will be a graduate. Sounds like fun. So I guess this is the best time to reveal 10 things I want to do before I die . Oh! sorry, before I graduate.
1. Google Summer Of Code Okay. First one should not be a surprise for computer students. Gsoc is like a dream for almost every computer engineering student.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>